<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lifestyle on echen's blog</title><link>https://dev.echen.io/categories/lifestyle/</link><description>Recent content in Lifestyle on echen's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dev.echen.io/categories/lifestyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lessons Learned in a Semester Gone By</title><link>https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/mirror-reflection.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Lessons Learned in a Semester Gone By" />&lt;p>A semester gone as quickly as it came. Allow me to take you along its momentous journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="six-lessons-learned">Six Lessons Learned&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="1-take-a-moment-to-reflect">1. Take a moment to reflect&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It has been a while since I seriously sat down and seriously thought about what has happened in my life recently. Over the last few months, there have been times of fireworks and times of gloom, and everything has rushed by so fast that I haven’t found the right moment to really think about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been aware for a while that I tend to ignore difficult and abstract things in my life by filling my free time with distractions. Whether it be mindlessly playing Tetris, fidgeting with a Rubik’s cube, or watching videos on YouTube, I constantly find a new way to drown out things I don’t want to think about, whether it be homework or problems with my relationships or daily life. Around two months ago, I attempted to remedy this bad habit by writing in a journal every night with the hope that it would force me to think about my day and what motivated me to do certain things. It was great at first, but I found myself writing more face-value recollections of events that passed instead of writing about my thoughts and emotions; when I tried to write more about the latter, I would end up writing too much, which made me unmotivated to continue journaling. After a few weeks, I started lagging behind schedule and eventually dropped it because I was “too busy.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like some of you might be the same. When was the last time you analyzed your current state: your current strengths and weaknesses, personal flaws, or future goals? How about just sitting down for 15 minutes at the end of the day to figure out what you did that day? While we’re preoccupied with what we think are pressing matters, we tend to distract ourselves from bigger underlying questions or issues that we might have, maybe ones that are more important or severe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modern technology has only made things worse. In the brief periods of free time I caught over the semester, I always spent it browsing mindlessly through Instagram, Reddit, or Twitter. It was a brainless activity I could distract myself with, so I wouldn’t have to think about the mountain of problems lying ahead. I would desperately scroll to find something even minutely interesting, hoping to distract myself from my problems. I could have devoted some time, any amount of time, to just sit and think. I could have put the phone down and just thought about something, anything. That’s all I had to do. But in those moments, I couldn’t. Not even for five minutes. I’m not saying that we don’t deserve breaks sometimes. After an intense study session or work period, I think it is perfectly fine to just turn your brain off as your body recuperates. But even setting a little amount of time to reflect is vital to your self and environmental awareness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s definitely not easy. I am filled with emotions that I do not understand and cannot convey, and trying to think through them is sometimes as difficult as preparing for an upcoming exam. I have tried to initiate a habit of personal reflections multiple times in the last few months but I couldn’t due to the stress that was piling up. After a while, I told myself I would wait until the school year was over so I could gather my thoughts and try again (which has led to what you are reading now). The less I reflect, the more my days become uniform and monotonous, turning into a sequence of rapid events that I can’t even remember.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, how do you begin the process of self-reflection? You can start small. Begin by recounting the important moments that passed today. If nothing happened today, then think about yesterday or the past week. Think about your behaviors, important events, or crucial conversations. Consider how you would like to improve, things that are holding you back, and what you hope to achieve. The answers to these questions might not be obvious, and it can take a long time before you’ve even figured yourself out. The sooner you start, the better. You don’t want a whole year to pass for you to realize that you aren’t at a place you want to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often find writing your thoughts on paper or a computer really helps this process. By making your ideas physical, you can refer back to them in the future, to see what progress you have made. It also provides a sense of accountability, as you subconsciously know that this “something” knows who you are and what you want. Another good way is to take a long walk on a brisk evening. Listen to the voice of nature or calming music. For some reason, I don’t think listening to Eminem’s Rap God stimulates the brain too well. It will likely allow you to destress, which makes thinking through difficult things much easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-have-an-honest-conversation-with-your-friend">2. Have an honest conversation with your friend&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Until this semester, I haven’t been seriously confronted by a friend for a mistake I made. Likewise, I have never seriously confronted a friend about a mistake they made. I have always expected others to initiate while I remained in the background, away from any direct controversy. Even though keeping silent might spare you a few uncomfortable situations here and there, it’s only going to manifest in resentment and frustration later down the line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your friends are people that you should be honest with. If you have a problem with them, you should be vocal about it. Even though we all cherish our friends, they aren’t perfect, and neither are we. Everyone has the capacity to improve. If you don’t speak out against bad behavior, you’re only going to prolong a problem, and nobody ends up satisfied. If you don’t tell me that I’m a piece of sh*t, then why would I try to change?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chances are, you might learn something new about your friend. You might not have understood them correctly, or maybe you failed to see their perspective. Don’t be so quick to assume that your diagnosis was valid. Being able to engage in productive criticism can only strengthen your relationships, as long as both parties are willing to listen. Dream of a friendship where both of you can initiate difficult conversations without fear. You will learn to give and take criticism, and you will become untouchable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still need to work on this. I am nowhere near where I would like to ideally be, but I must practice what I preach. I know I am faint of heart, constantly overthinking about how others perceive me and fearing I will disappoint my friends. I vouch to be honest, and I will reap the consequences of my behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a problem with a friend, and you’ve been trying to tell them for a long time now, rip the band-aid off.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-take-a-step-back-look-at-the-bigger-picture">3. Take a step back, look at the bigger picture&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I wanted to start my year with a bang. Too long during quarantine spent lounging around, wasting time, and waking up at two in the afternoon. This year was going to be different. After a mild start during the &lt;a class="link" href="http://echen.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>first semester&lt;/a>, I wanted to work hard and achieve a lot during the second. I dedicated myself to demanding clubs and filled most of my free time with “work.” I began to stress myself out, and I was not suited to handle the massive workload.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/car.jpg"
width="1699"
height="1274"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/car_hu15173cecb2a96d36255c48e9a0c4f72f_693154_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/car_hu15173cecb2a96d36255c48e9a0c4f72f_693154_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Completed formula car for Terps Racing"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were moments when I considered whether I wanted to continue with the clubs. I was sacrificing time to do other things that I wanted to do: study machine learning, write blogs, read books, etc. I considered their career benefits and often convinced myself that I was doing the right thing. But subconsciously, I felt like I was giving up other important things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless, I don’t have any regrets. I was also able to meet friends and learn a lot about things completely unrelated to my major. I was able to figure out what I like and don’t like, which I believe to be a crucial part of the college experience. I wouldn’t go back and change anything, because chances are, they shaped me into the person I am today. But there is definitely a moral of the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you do anything, you should always ask yourself, “what do I want and what will I achieve by doing this?” You should be honest with yourself. Do things that you find meaningful and do it because you want to. Don’t volunteer for a children’s hospital because think it will make you virtuous to your friends. Volunteer there if you actually like working with children and want to make a difference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You also should commit yourself to what you find valuable, not what others would find valuable. If you want to dedicate your evenings to journaling or drawing, more power to you. Part of me hoped people would admire me for taking a bunch of clubs on at the same time, but I think I missed the bigger point by assuming that mindset. Don’t let others’ perceptions of what is important affect the way you conduct yourself. You know yourself the best, after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="leaving-it-on-a-personal-note">Leaving it on a personal note&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For my clubs, I always felt a pang of guilt whenever I considered dropping them next semester, to the point where I would lie to myself that I actually wanted to be there (metaphorically speaking; I loved hanging out with my club buddies). Although they are fun and challenging, I don’t think I got exactly what I truly wanted. I didn’t want to let my teammates down, so I made commitments of returning to the club next year purely from &lt;em>guilt.&lt;/em> That is not a position anyone should ever want to be in. You’ll keep yourself held back, blocked by a barrier you set up yourself. Decide what you want to do and commit to it. Your time is valuable. Don’t waste it for somebody else’s sake.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This doesn’t mean I’ll drop the clubs I am in now. I think it takes a lot more careful consideration. They are very valuable experiences, and I have gained more than I could have expected. I’m just saying that I will have to carefully decide what I hope to achieve in the coming years, and I will have to decide whether these clubs align with my ideal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-face-your-fears-head-on">4. Face your fears head-on&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/fear.jpg"
width="750"
height="750"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/fear_hu916537752a1084a1f34a52b82a0aa51e_106976_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/fear_hu916537752a1084a1f34a52b82a0aa51e_106976_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of mymodernmet.com"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many nights, I think about the upcoming deadlines and I feel an impending sense of doom. Maybe I have two meetings lined up, a project that’s due, an email that I need to respond to, or a presentation I need to give. Sometimes in the midst of a mild anxiety attack, I would think about all the items that I needed to complete, thinking &lt;em>Oh! That’s not that much&lt;/em>. I would regain some confidence before quickly returning to panic mode. I started to question why I had brief moments of composure interspersed in my moments of panic. It’s because I was usually right about there not being much to do. At least, it was much more manageable than my panicking brain was suggesting. But all that fear racing in my head prevented me from thinking straight, as my mind continuously cycled through everything that could go wrong. Often, it would lead me to believe that was more trouble ahead than there actually was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are in a stressful frenzy, take some time to define what is worrying you. Express the fears on paper. Maybe it’s a project that’s due, your massive student loans, a friend who’s being an ass. If you let your fear control you, your brain will constantly cycle through your problems to the extent where you feel like you have more problems than you actually do. By writing them down, you know what lies ahead, and you can focus on tackling them instead of being in a continual state of worry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having a physical representation of your fears also prevents you from constantly rationalizing doomsday scenarios. We try to distract ourselves from our difficult tasks, which only temporarily relieves us of stress. The second you think about them again, you have to recount everything on your agenda, which will wear you down. By putting your fears on paper, you can skip that step, which will give you a ton of mental headroom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can take this further. You can write down the worst-case scenarios out as well. What’s the worst thing that could happen if you go ask your boss for a raise? Maybe she’ll laugh at you and tell you that you are the laziest employee in the building. Well, that’s not so bad, right? With that out of the way, you can now contemplate how to avoid the worst-case scenario. Or even if you do meet the worst-case scenario, have a plan to cope and deal with it. Having this sort of mental plan will keep you at ease, as you will at minimum have something planned in all cases, even if it isn’t particularly good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may seem obvious. If you tell me that it sounds like I’m advocating for you to manage your tasks, you’d be right. But it’s also more than that. Your fears don’t always have to be something tangible, like a project. Your fears might be related to problems with your family, confronting a friend about their behavior, or a big presentation you have next week. Having a disaster plan for those is just as important as your everyday tasks and routines. By simply physically establishing what is bothering you, you can overcome your toughest challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A lot of this advice is adapted from Tim Ferriss, an established self-help author, podcaster, and entrepreneur. I recommend checking some of his works out, such as &lt;em>The 4-Hour Workweek&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="5-love-the-process-and-the-results-will-come">5. Love the process and the results will come&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A goal-oriented life might not be a bad thing, but it misses the point. You don’t want to spend your days chasing the next goal. You delegate feelings of achievement to temporary moments of success. What happens after you meet a goal? You have to chase the next one until your life becomes an endless pursuit of empty goals. A goal is only a temporary milestone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your goal is to lose 10 pounds, what do you do after you lose the 10 pounds? Many people think they’re done and end back right where they started. So, what do you do instead? Well, let’s analyze why you wanted to lose 10 pounds in the first place? It was probably a desire to be healthier, fitter, and more attractive. The 10-pound loss was just a façade for the desire to be healthy. By focusing on the ends, we often ignore the means. If you start to run to lose weight, don’t stop once you reach your weight loss goal. Let yourself &lt;em>become&lt;/em> a runner. Let your identity morph into the ideal. Not only will you learn to love running, but you also won’t stop simply because you lost an arbitrary amount of weight. Running will become part of your lifestyle. This is how I learned to love going to the gym. I never had a goal in sight. I just wanted to be more fit. The more I told people I went to the gym, the more it became a part of me. It was no longer something I had to consciously think of doing. Since I embed it into my identity, I no longer had to struggle to convince myself to go every night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn’t to say that you shouldn’t have goals. I still have goals, but I focus on the process instead of the goal itself. You should too. If you want to win a business competition, focus on being a better businessman. Pride yourself on being able to make connections and initiate conversations. Naturally, regardless of whether you win, you will become a better businessman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to start reading books, don’t just set a goal of reading one book. Convince yourself that you are a reader and that you read for enjoyment. If you learn to love reading itself, one book is no longer enough. If you focus only on just finishing that one book, you’ll miss the whole point of the book, and you think you’ll be satisfied. But it won’t convert you into a reader.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still have goals, but make them secondary to the process. Or orient your goal such that you can never truly meet it. Even if you don’t meet your goals, you’ll have changed yourself for the better. I think this quote is a good note to end on:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If successful and unsuccessful people share the same goals, then the goal cannot be what differentiates the winners from the losers.&amp;rdquo; - James Clear, &lt;em>Atomic Habits&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="6-remove-jealousy-and-resentment-from-your-life">6. Remove jealousy and resentment from your life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://media.swncdn.com/cms/BST/29983-cain-slaying-abel-jacopo-palma-1590.800w.tn.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of biblestudytools.com"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of biblestudytools.com&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jealousy is an innate and natural thing. It’s easy to feel jealous or resent the friend that has all A’s, a prestigious internship, and a full-ride tuition. You’ve been there, I’ve been there, we’ve all been there. It’s not necessarily a bad thing. These “perfect” friends embody what we want for ourselves. Jealousy might be a positive motivator for you to chase your own goals. But let it out of control, and you will become bitter and dissatisfied. Even today, I still feel a twinge of jealousy when I hear about my friends’ new achievements. But rather than breeding resentment, it allows me to push myself to achieve more. Here are some tips to change your mindset:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Success isn’t a zero-sum game&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally, &lt;em>your friend’s success doesn’t take away anything from you.&lt;/em> Just because your friend Abel got a new promotion doesn’t mean you can’t get one. Scarcity doesn’t apply when it comes to achievements. You have your whole life ahead to accomplish things that Abel cannot, and vice versa. If Abel finds success, then go find your own success.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I guess this doesn’t apply if he starts dating your crush&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You’re not even playing the same game&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why are you comparing yourself to Abel? You’re living your own life, not his. He might want to become a research scientist while you want to become a rocket engineer. You’re walking on two separate tracks. The benchmarks for his success are not the same as yours. You aren’t on the same timeline, and opportunities will manifest in your life at different rates. You must have patience and persevere at your own pace, not at Abel’s. You do the best you can do, as your life is your own. As Jordan Peterson said, “compare yourself to the person you were yesterday, not to who someone is today.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Abel might be better than you&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, sorry to say, but it might be true. Maybe at that one thing, Abel is just better than you. Maybe he put in more work, more time, and more energy to achieve that one thing. There are plenty of things that you are probably better than Abel at. It also isn’t too late to catch up, either. Even if you think you outclass him in every way, but somehow he is doing better than you, don’t let that affect how you perceive yourself. Life isn’t fair. Accept it and move on. If you think that life is fair, then you will only find despair. Focus on the things you can actually control, and luck will find you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Do you even know Abel?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this moment in time, would you trade your life with Abel’s? At a surface glance, maybe you determine that everything in his life is better than yours, so would you make the switch? Probably not, and you probably don’t want to either. Everybody deals with different struggles in their life. If you swapped with Abel, you would probably be in a whole new world of hurt, a world you probably didn’t know existed. You deal with things that others don’t, and only you could understand how to cope with the pain. Don’t be so quick to assume that someone else’s life is more glamorous than yours. In a particular moment, maybe Abel exudes success. But that moment is temporary. Look at the bigger picture.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You want the best for Abel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, he is your friend. Would you be happier had he never received the promotion? Of course not. He wants the best for you, and you want the best for him. It’s always okay to feel jealousy. To some extent, you cannot control what your brain is programmed to feel. But you can channel the feelings in a new way. Use Abel’s good fortune as a springboard for yours. Be proud of him, and use that energy to motivate yourself even more. If both of you can sustain this positive feedback loop, then who in the world can stop you?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="a-conclusion">A conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Life is a long run. Don’t let your jealousy control your life. A feeling of worth should stem from within, not from how you compare to others around you. When you grow old, you hope to stand on a mountain that you climbed yourself. You want to feel that the journey made you into a better person than the person you were before, not a person better than some random Abel somewhere else.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-motivates-me">What Motivates Me?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/growth.jpg"
width="520"
height="214"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/growth_hu8251970078283c6533463f8c95cc279a_42243_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/growth_hu8251970078283c6533463f8c95cc279a_42243_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of osnatfineart.com"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="242"
data-flex-basis="583px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why do I do the things that I do? What do I truly want?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often find myself thinking of pursuing the most lucrative jobs in order to make the highest income. But on the inside, I shouldn’t care. Many people benchmark status with salary, which seems to influence me to pick certain occupations over others. But who cares if I’m making 100K more than the guy next door or my best friend? My salary isn’t going to be written on my tombstone. My quality of life won’t be dictated by marginal increases in income.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know myself. I’m a learner in heart and spirit. I crave understanding the world and nothing brings more satisfaction to me than learning something mind-boggling. If you ask my closest friends, they can attest to me spouting nonsensical facts on the daily, often to the point of annoyance. I tell people that if money wasn’t an issue, I would be majoring in astronomy and physics. But why? It seems that those two subjects have blown my mind the most amount of times, and I connect with them. But obviously, money must come into consideration. With my love of technology and working within teams, computer engineering was the most logical choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What should the takeaway be? My primary motivation seems to come from a deep desire to learn and understand. A career- and specialization-oriented society seems to conflict with this goal, but perhaps not. I will always be a student first. Regardless of what career I end up pursuing, that will not stop me from learning. But, in order to love what I do, I must find a career that makes me want to continue learning. Its principles must align with the drive that turns my inner gears.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this essay I submitted for my QUEST application best encapsulates how I want to approach life, ignoring the portions that are tailored to QUEST itself (and the cringe).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every day last year, I found myself staring at a notebook filled with all the things I wanted to learn: Japanese history, cryptocurrency, astrophysics, and photography. After sorting out my priorities, these desires were often left on the backburner until further notice. Even when I was applying to college, I was faced with the difficult task of dedicating the next four years to one area of expertise. Even if I try to dedicate time to learning new things, there is simply not enough time to absorb everything out there.
However, this does not mean I cannot diversify the intellect in my life. As I move through my career, I aim to drag my sleigh of understanding through different industries, collecting the experiences and expertise of people from all walks of life. Through these endeavors, I hope to truly be connected to the heart of society. QUEST would provide an entry into the collaborative world between engineers and businesspeople, igniting my journey to perceive the world. Through collaboration and deliberation, I hope to build lasting relationships and connections with a passionate group of students. If knowledge is truly power, then I want to be powerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h1 id="how-have-i-changed">How have I changed?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="personal-improvement">Personal Improvement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What strides have I made this semester? In terms of personal growth, I think I have bettered myself more in the last 6 months than I have over the entirety of high school. I dug in my heels this semester and pushed myself toward my goals. I would like to discuss them as personal milestones. That means this isn’t just an excuse for me to brag.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="accepted-into-quest">Accepted into QUEST&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I was accepted into QUEST, an honors program for collaborative business and engineering consulting and quality assurance. I’ve always wanted some business-oriented classes incorporated into my educational experience, and I think I’ll find that here. There seem to be many intelligent and motivated individuals here, and I hope to learn a lot from them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I wrote a few decent essays for the application, and I was very happy with my responses during the interview portion. I recommend any freshman students to apply, as the program is a great way to develop your career.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rhsmith.umd.edu/quest" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rhsmith.umd.edu/quest&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="found-clubs-i-could-dedicate-my-time-to">Found clubs I could dedicate my time to&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I won’t touch too much on them here, as I’ve probably rambled about them ad-nauseam at this point. But I’m happy to say I was very involved with the school this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="became-sub-team-leader-of-the-liquid-rocket-team">Became sub-team leader of the Liquid Rocket Team&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The liquid rocket team is the newest addition to the engineering club family this year. I was very afraid of applying to be a team lead, as I had very little experience or understanding of the daunting tasks that lay ahead. I saw that the team was impressed with some of my work in the first semester, so I gathered the courage to apply. I ended up being the only person to apply for the Data Acquisition Lead, so I got the position. Good thing too, as it plays a critical role in the overall team. I’m proud that I applied to a leadership role as a freshman, even though it wasn’t a particularly difficult feat.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="won-the-northrop-grumman-environmental-sustainability-challenge">Won the Northrop Grumman Environmental Sustainability Challenge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/shovel.jpg"
width="956"
height="1274"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/shovel_hu5cbf5469988e986eaf35370c3a18067a_540759_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/shovel_hu5cbf5469988e986eaf35370c3a18067a_540759_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Shoveling a streambed for our prototype"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, kind of a flex. We won $2,500. A class member in Terps Racing made a post on the club Slack channel, announcing that she had a good idea for some environmental challenge and was looking for team members. The thought of joining circulated through my mind for an entire week. I was already swamped with my other clubs, but I was sure that an opportunity like this might never arise again. Sophie already had an established idea, the hardest part of any challenge. I remember talking to my roommate, Jason, at night about joining. He told me I would be an idiot for adding another club to my relatively busy schedule, and I agreed. But like the idiot that I am (or a stroke of genius), I decided to talk to Sophie and join her team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it turned out great. We traveled to D.C. every Saturday to build a prototype IoT stormwater management system on a friend’s residential property. We poured in hours of work, putting huge amounts of effort into the prototype as well as the final presentation materials. We knew we had something special, and we went all in. When we finally presented to the panel of judges, we were confident that our idea and presentation quality trumped all of the other teams. And we won. What an incredible feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="went-to-the-gym">Went to the gym&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/gym.png"
width="698"
height="1258"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/gym_hu10014e64974507ce08c6ff6ff437a66b_1146154_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/gym_hu10014e64974507ce08c6ff6ff437a66b_1146154_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="55"
data-flex-basis="133px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I made a hard commitment to go to the gym to become more fit. I wanted to build muscle and exercise every day. I never imagined that I would keep up with this resolution, but I did (look to lesson 5 above). Even though I’ve taken a few week-long breaks from sickness and injury, I’ve maintained a healthy gym schedule, and I’m proud of myself for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="committed-to-being-a-better-man">Committed to being a better man&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I cannot overstate how important this was to me. I changed my mindset completely. I knew I was capable of a lot more, and I tried harder to achieve what I wanted than I ever have before. I dedicated myself to working on my flaws, working on my strengths, and pursuing opportunities I would have brushed off in the past. This mentality helped me adapt to the increase in workload and struggle through periods of adversity. Even today, I am trying to do even more than I did yesterday. Even with moments of laziness and outbursts of insecurity, I truly believe I am headed down a good path.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I don’t think I could have ever made a statement this bold or overconfident in the past. Let’s just say I’m being woefully optimistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="flaws">Flaws&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is much room for improvement. Let me highlight a couple of bad habits and behaviors that continue to plague my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="focusing-on-the-unimportant">Focusing on the unimportant&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I often fill my time with “work” just so I can feel productive. I see productivity as a means to feeling productive. Instead of having the focus on getting important work done, I merely work on mundane and meaningless work just to feel like I’m doing something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, I’ll spend 3 hours organizing my schedule instead of doing the MATLAB project that’s due tomorrow. I’ll browse the internet looking for new books to read instead of reading the books I have on my table. Even though you might consider these things “productive,” they are not important. There’s no need for me to put up a façade of productivity if I’m only going to waste my time. I need to prioritize as well. I also deserve breaks and leisure time. I shouldn’t lie to myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="i-dont-need-validation">I don’t need validation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Why do I need people to tell me that I’m good at something to know that I am good at that something? That feeling of value should come from within. I constantly seek validation to feel like I’m worthy. This needs to stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been struggling with inner confidence for a long time. I constantly doubt my ability to do things well, and I always fear that people see me as less incapable than I truly am. It’s like a paradox. I don’t think I am good at something, but I also want other people to acknowledge that I am good at it. I’m not saying praise isn’t good. I like it, and so does everybody else. But I should’ve derived my own value solely from it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This works both ways. Validation can also lead to overconfidence. Often, people will tell me I did a great job, even if what I did was relatively mundane. I shouldn’t overvalue what others have to say. My perception of the quality of my work should determine how I should feel about it. Constant praise and admiration will demotivate me from pushing myself forward. If I can survive socially on mediocrity, then what desire do I have to become better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone tells Bob that he is good at something, I also shouldn’t be so insecure that I need to ask if they think I am also good at that something. I will only come off as an unconfident beta-male. That’s not who I want to be. I don’t need my grandma to tell me I’m handsome to know that I’m the sexiest person on the planet. I already know that I am.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-struggle-with-failure">The struggle with failure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I am not good at accepting failure. It often makes me incredibly angry at myself, even if I knew I tried my best. It makes me insecure and leads me to think bad thoughts about others. It’s a bad mentality and certainly a manifestation of the wrong mindset. I am not too sure how I plan to deal with this, but I cannot let the anger control me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="not-everyone-cares-about-me">Not everyone cares about me&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Sounds a bit harsh, but true. I fascinate myself with unusual facts about the universe, politics, and interesting tidbits about psychological abstraction. I tell my friends these things with passion, and I am often met with puzzled faces and annoyance. Why? Because I ignore the fact that they could not give any less of a sh*t about how Hawaii was formed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to give people space and put myself second sometimes. I don’t want to risk my friends becoming uncomfortable or annoyed to satisfy my own selfish desires.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="i-am-not-holier-than-thou">I am not holier than thou&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As much as I think I’m an angel from heaven, I am not. I am not morally better than anybody else on the planet. I might think I am smarter than you, but I am probably wrong. I convince myself that I never think in this way, but I am lying to myself. I don’t understand the circumstances that govern your life. I am just an individual on the planet with my strengths and weaknesses. And you are another.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="forgetful-fool">Forgetful fool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I forget things so easily. Just got back into my dorm. Where are my keys? Where’s my wallet? I forgot my meeting an hour ago?! Oh no! This was a constant headache for me, and I can’t even imagine how many times I peeved at Jason or my other friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was quite certain I had ADHD at some point, so I attributed my forgetfulness to it. I was evaluated by a psychiatrist, who said it was likely as well. But after taking a concentration test, it seems that I don’t. But the psychiatrist seems unsure, too. I will either get a second opinion because she’s telling me that I might have anxiety problems, too. I don’t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Either way, I can remedy this by meditating more and being more organized with my stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ending-note">Ending note&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is by no means an exhaustive list. These were the things that stood out to me the most. You can be sure to let me know of any others, and I will be as perceptive to your criticisms as possible. Thank you, my lovely fans.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="did-i-reach-my-goals">Did I reach my goals?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I set a few goals in my &lt;a class="link" href="https://echen.io/blog/2021-10-23-two-months-into-school" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>UMD post&lt;/a> in the fall. Let’s see how I measured up.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-straight-as">Get Straight A’s&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Close, but no cigar. It seems like I overestimated my ability to focus on school and extracurriculars concurrently. Nothing below an A-, however.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="find-a-club-i-am-passionate-about">Find a club I am passionate about&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This one is a bit more tricky. In many regards, I found what I was looking for in SEDS, Terps Racing, and an environment sustainability challenge I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They didn’t have everything I want. Mostly, I don’t know if I could find a profession in the things I did in these clubs. However, they were amazing learning experiences and provided me with great friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="make-new-friends">Make new friends&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/enes100.jpg"
width="756"
height="568"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/enes100_hu10674a5f77683763bd4cf0a2453f3d70_143765_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/enes100_hu10674a5f77683763bd4cf0a2453f3d70_143765_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Engineering Group Team Hangout"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="319px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accomplished! To name a few: Max, Ryan, and Sam from Terps Racing. Mohammad, Dev, Bobby from SEDS. Eyobed, Richard, and Sophie from the environmental challenge. Brian Ding. Everyone in my ENES100 group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to find even more in the future. I have more culturally diverse friends now than I ever had before. Woo-hoo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are still different kinds of friends that I am still looking for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Motivates me to push myself to extremes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loves learning, reading, and talking about all things science&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dances&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Willing to openly discuss politics and challenge my beliefs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="get-an-internship">Get an Internship&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Success! I landed one at Mailchimp, a marketing and email company! If you check your subscription emails, there is a chance that it was sent via Mailchimp. I am doing Machine Learning Infrastructure (MLOps), which essentially means I am creating the tools for the data scientists to use so they can better understand CPMs and market effectiveness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It starts next Monday (6/13), and I am very excited! Mailchimp has been extremely organized, communitive, and welcoming. I am studying up on the Google Cloud Platform, and I am liking it more and more every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll discuss some perks that came with the job. Mailchimp was acquired by Intuit, a public software company, in 2021 for $12 billion in stock and cash. I received a hefty living stipend of $5000, which I would attribute to the increase in the budget due to the acquisition. The pay is also not bad, either. I went through 3 rounds of interviews: an introductory interview with the talent scout, a personality/technical interview with the manager and MLOps lead, and a technical team interview with 3 members of the MLOps team. I think I did a pretty good job of being likable, which is how I got the position.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was negotiating with Astranis (a geosatellite “startup”) during my acceptance period with Mailchimp. They moved my interview to an earlier date upon my request. I had a personality and scenario-based technical interview with the ground software lead and a coding interview with another member of the software team. I did excellently in the first interview, but my relative inexperience with Pythonic data structures showed in the second interview. I was able to get the “right answer” but only after a series of hints. Honestly, it’s probably a blessing that I ended up committing to Mailchimp, since I did not know about the stipend yet. However, being in-person in San Francisco at a booming aerospace company would have had its perks as well…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other offers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Terminix, a pest control company: AWS architecture, great interview process, cool team, unfortunately low pay, no clout in the tech industry&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KBP, an engineering contractor: AWS architecture, scary interviewer, sped talk during the interview, got the position only after I accepted Mailchimp, low pay for a solutions architect&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The biggest differentiator I think I had compared to other candidates is my &lt;a class="link" href="https://echen.io/blog/2021-07-08-my-journey-with-amazon-web-serivces" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>AWS certification&lt;/a>, as all my offers were cloud engineering positions. I highly recommend getting it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-a-girlfriend">Get a Girlfriend&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Haha, nope.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="read-a-textbook-on-all-the-basic-sciences">Read a textbook on all the basic sciences&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I knew this goal would be a stretch, and I was very right. I wish I had the time to read all the textbooks, and it hurts my heart that I probably will never, at least not for a long time. In order to maintain a balanced life, this goal will probably be sent to the backburner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still will strive to read through them throughout my lifetime. It probably just won’t happen during college. To make a plan, I’ll start with Caroll and Ostlie’s &lt;em>Astrophysics&lt;/em> first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="start-new-projects">Start new projects&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This goal wasn’t particularly detailed or good. It wasn’t super actionable, and is an example of “easier said than done.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Either way, I am pleased to say that I adhered to it pretty well in the second semester regardless. Two projects come to mind:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ENES100, Engineering Design Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Northrop Grumman Sustainability Challenge&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="continue-playing-violin">Continue playing violin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I did play some violin this semester, but not in a productive way. I would blaze through pieces one by one until exhaustion without improving my technique. It’s nice to have fun, but I also want to be good. Starting next year, I will try to incorporate disciplined practice into my playing schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="goals-for-the-summer">Goals for the Summer&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>These might not adhere to the principles I explained in lesson 5 above. But I haven’t completely established the framework I want to use to “achieve” these goals yet, either. That will take some careful consideration if I want to make these things habits.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="become-a-dancer">Become a dancer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I just wanna be cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="continue-going-to-the-gym">Continue going to the gym&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A gym rat, I shall become.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="become-a-morning-person">Become a morning person&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I hate sleeping late. I hate the feeling of being tired the entire day. I hate wasting my time. I will change.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="build-a-personal-portfolio-website">Build a personal portfolio website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I want to show off some of the things I have accomplished. It’s more of an excuse to write about them as a part of self-reflection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reader-reader-reader">Reader reader reader&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have begun reading books. I made a commitment to 2 books a month, but I am dropping that now. I will just read in my free time. Read whenever I can. I love it, so why set arbitrary deadlines for myself? I want to build a habit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="continue-along-my-writing-journey">Continue along my writing journey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This blog post is very different than the ones I have written previously. I have definitely crawled out of my shell, and I now have the confidence to share very deep insights into my life. I want to keep writing about the things that I love and expand to even more topics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that’s good enough for now. I will definitely write about my progress in future posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This semester was an emotional ride. Many times did I succumb to the harsh environment I put myself in, and many times did I rise to the top. On a personal level, I learned a lot about myself and the person I want to be. I made many friends and created lasting memories. And I have no regrets. I’m glad I did the things I did this semester, and I look forward to the next.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-dedication-to-spice">A Dedication to Spice&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/spice.jpg"
width="1699"
height="1274"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/spice_huce4e143c927c37a29d14bbf7626d29ca_345621_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/lessons-learned-in-a-semester-gone-by/spice_huce4e143c927c37a29d14bbf7626d29ca_345621_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As many of you might have heard, my family had to put down our cat, Spice, on March 30, 2022. He fought longer than any vet expected and lived a happy life. He was the best pet I could have ever asked for, along with his sister, Sugar, who is doing well. I miss you, buddy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.notion.so/ericchen314/Lessons-Learned-in-a-Semester-Gone-By-43102540d34e49e28b2000633eb913ef" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Read the notion version!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two Months at UMD!</title><link>https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been at the University of Maryland for two months now! Here is a recap of everything that has happened so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="first-week-shenanigans">First Week Shenanigans&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="moving-into-the-dorm">Moving into the Dorm&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first day was pretty exciting. I finally was going to crawl out of my shell and venture somewhere new— no more parental supervision, new friends, and a new environment. I drove with my mom to the Xfinity Center at UMD and picked up my new ID (with a horrible photo), the keys to my dorm, and a small welcome package with chips, drink mix, and a few stickers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We drove to my new dorm, located at Pyon-Chen hall in the Ellicott Community. I was pretty pumped, as my roommate Jason Liu and I would be residing in the fresh-built dorm at UMD. It stood out immediately: a rectangular and modern-looking white and black building, covered in tall and slim reflective windows. The architecture did not match any of the other buildings in the vicinity, which were red brick buildings, with less flashy windows and visible heating units.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mom and I grabbed a cart and started moving my luggage up the stairs to the fourth floor. I was able to meet my floor&amp;rsquo;s RAs, Sam and Joyce, who were welcoming the new residents at the front of the building. As we slowly ascended the escalators, I was struck with uneasiness. This new building would be my home. How long would it take for me to become familiar with the campus? Would I do well in my classes? Who are my new friends going to be? I was brought back to reality as the elevator&amp;rsquo;s voice announced that we had reached floor 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After fumbling with the lock for two minutes, I finally entered my room. It was much larger than my friend Iris&amp;rsquo;s dorm, who attends Johns Hopkins, yet smaller than I thought it was going to be. Naively so, as it is absolutely massive compared to other people at my school. I should have appreciated what I had more. I do now. Signs of growth, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I unpacked a bit, neatly organizing my clothes and an unnecessary amount of accessories and gadgets that I brought with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0566-min.jpg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0566-min_hudaaef5fd5ad17f22631e35f45c5ace31_976312_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0566-min_hudaaef5fd5ad17f22631e35f45c5ace31_976312_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Me and Jason&amp;rsquo;s room at Pyon-Chen"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jason arrived an hour later. He unpacked for a little while, and our parents left shortly after. It was surreal. We would finally be settling down in a new place. I would see him day in and day out. I sighed out in excitement and relief. I finally had the freedom I was hoping for throughout the entire summer. Like the idiots we were, we just stayed in our room for hours until our other Blair friends arrived instead of exploring campus or meeting with our neighbors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first week is a good time to reconnect with old friends, make new ones, and just explore campus. Let your excitement course through you. Do what you want, as you only have a few days before the dreaded classes begin.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="meeting-old-friends">Meeting Old Friends&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A lot of my middle school and high school friends go to UMD, and I had a lot of catching up to do. I first met up with my Blair friends: Yuri, Christina, Evan, et cetera. Despite being friends for 4+ years, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten much closer with them. We spend a lot of time eating together, shopping, and watching movies together. Like one big happy family. I&amp;rsquo;ve reconnected with friends from middle school, like Shakti, Brant, Brian, and Alan. I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot more people, but so far, I&amp;rsquo;ve only become close with a few.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My newest close friend is Stephanie. We clicked instantly the day we met, and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen her almost every day since. She practically lives in our room now, mooching on our A/C, using my water boiler, doing her homework, and being annoying. Just kidding. I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have met her, since we&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of things together, like going to the first-look fair, eating off-campus, painting our nails, playing violin, and much more. It&amp;rsquo;s been really fun, and I look forward to the next four years together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/steff.png"
width="596"
height="747"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/steff_hu3ad6cf7966e2200b1d3dbdd3198805c9_752836_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/steff_hu3ad6cf7966e2200b1d3dbdd3198805c9_752836_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Me and Steph in CHEM 135"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="79"
data-flex-basis="191px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love how I have every day to spend time with friends. Although being relatively quiet around strangers, I can&amp;rsquo;t stand being alone. I&amp;rsquo;m so fortunate to be able to spend time doing daily activities and going to classes with the people I love most, which is the best part of college so far. I look forward to making new friends, as I desperately need to develop new relationships and expand my social circle. But currently, I&amp;rsquo;m too reserved. I aim to change that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="reviewing-my-courses">Reviewing my Courses&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>First, some context. I am planning on majoring in Computer Engineering, but I am currently a Computer Science student. I will be transferring to the engineering department in the following semester, given that I do not bomb the classes I am currently taking. Here is a summary of the classes and what I think about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="major-requirements">Major Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="cmsc-216---intro-to-computer-systems">CMSC 216 - Intro to Computer Systems&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A class on computer systems, where we learn the fundamental concepts that enable programs to execute on real hardware. We are currently learning the C programming language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/EIFEpnEXkAAc5_p.jpg"
width="1200"
height="900"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/EIFEpnEXkAAc5_p_hu0245f03a3b91e68ec75ccd5395555b71_228234_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/EIFEpnEXkAAc5_p_hu0245f03a3b91e68ec75ccd5395555b71_228234_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The Computer Science Building: Brendan Iribe Center"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m taking the course with Professor Jose Calderon. The class is in the Antonov auditorium at the Brendan Iribe Center, which is a very large and modern building. There are around 200 students in lecture and around 30 students in each section. Jose presents lectures using PowerPoints on the front screens, taking questions every now and then. He explains things extremely clearly with great enunciation. He provides witty and quippy remarks all the time and it always makes the class chuckle. Each new concept in the slides comes with example code, which is very helpful for understanding concepts. Each lecture is formulaic, with all the content prepared on the course website, ready with all the presentations and homework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discussions are usually pretty uninspiring. Some important discussions go over topics like Linux commands and valgrind, but they are pretty slow-paced and kind of awkward. There is definitely value in them, but I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly look forward to them. My TA, Keonwoo, is pretty cool, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each week is typically accompanied by a coding project or exercise. They&amp;rsquo;re pretty standard and not very hard, but quite time-consuming. Debugging can take a long time for some of the projects, as C is annoying as heck. You submit projects through a server called Grace, which is hosted on grace.umd.edu (port 22 access only), where you must pass public tests, release tests, and sometimes secret tests. Your code is graded on styling and comment as well. You are given 3 tokens per 24 hours to test the release tests, so they need to be used wisely (it also rewards doing the projects earlier).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worst part about the course is definitely the slow grading. It&amp;rsquo;s been a month since the first exercise and weeks after multiple quizzes and projects, and only one assignment has been returned. Speed it up, please :(.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for exams, I bombed the first one, haha. Good (or bad) thing, most people did. I did multiple practice exams, which were all of similar difficulties, and then the real midterm just slapped me to the moon. It was significantly more complicated and intricate, and I did not finish. I was also not sure of any of my answers to the supposedly easier questions. Jose and the TAs really threw us a curveball. However, they recognized the problem, and hopefully, it will be curved. I still think I failed, sadly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall rating:&lt;/strong> 4.5 stars.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="chem-135---engineering-chemistry">CHEM 135 - Engineering Chemistry&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An introductory chemistry course for Engineers. A little more fast-paced than the basic introductory chemistry course, but with no laboratory and exclusively for engineering students. The class is in the big chemistry lecture hall, with around 200-300 students in the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My professor is Dr. Elizabeth Griffith. She feels like a high school teacher. She treats us in a very endearing and childish way. For example, she&amp;rsquo;ll tease us about drinking, ask us how our weekend was, and get the majority opinion before extending due dates. Despite being in a giant lecture hall filled with students, the environment feels rather friendly. Unlike in some of my other classes, the room isn&amp;rsquo;t dead silent before class starts, which is great. Less awkward for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dr. Griffith also teaches like a high school teacher. She explains things in simple terms— straight and to the point. She explains most concepts quite well, but to limited depth in my opinion. The course is pretty packed with material, one semester encompasses an entire year of AP Chemistry. Despite this, the classes do not feel that fast; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty manageable, as long as you pay attention and attend discussions to do practice problems. The best thing about this class is that there is no 3-hour laboratory each week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do attend both lectures and discussions, but I mostly learn by reading Peter Atkin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.macmillanlearning.com/college/us/product/Chemical-Principles/p/1464183953" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Chemical Principles&lt;/a>. This is part of my grand plan to become a genius (see &lt;a class="link" href="#Goals" >goals&lt;/a> below). It goes into more detail about topics covered in class, and it&amp;rsquo;s served me well so far. I don&amp;rsquo;t find the course particularly difficult, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the common opinion (this is partly because I&amp;rsquo;ve taken an intro to chemistry in the past). Many people on Reddit complain about the difficulty of the course, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s greatly overblown. The average grade on the first midterm was a 70%, which isn&amp;rsquo;t great, but not terrible either. It will require some work, but don&amp;rsquo;t let this scare you out of pursuing engineering. The best way to get help is to consult the professor during office hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall rating:&lt;/strong> 4.5 stars.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="math-246h---intro-to-differential-equations">MATH 246H - Intro to Differential Equations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Honors class for introductory differential equations. I doubt the honors distinction makes a difference; it&amp;rsquo;s probably just a smaller class. There are 22 spots in the course, but some will drop after the first midterm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The classroom environment is pretty unsocial. Every time I arrive in the room, it is so silent you could probably hear a mouse&amp;rsquo;s heartbeat. The professor shows up a few minutes before class starts and cuts right to the chase. His name is Christian Zickert and I have pretty mixed feelings about him and the course in general. I took Differential Equations in my junior year, so I am technically retaking the class (it didn&amp;rsquo;t cover all the necessary material, however). The class is relatively straightforward, perhaps a little bit disorganized. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean this in the traditional sense, as we cover material in a reasonable order, but I usually can&amp;rsquo;t tell the direction the material is building up to. To give an analogy, it&amp;rsquo;s like I&amp;rsquo;m given puzzle pieces to a puzzle, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know what picture I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of the students in my class are usually confused during class; this was pretty clear when the professor announced the average grade on the first midterm, which was an F. The professor spent much of the following class sort of roasting us, as he claims he reiterated the common mistakes on the exam, which were apparently very common for our section. To be fair, I believe he did a fair job of warning us about the performance on the first exam. He always tries to get us to understand the full picture, which is a good thing, but most people seem to still be confused. His personality is pretty quirky and unapproachable, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty difficult for most people to ask for advice outside of class time. However, I think his explanations during class are quite decent, but I seem to stand in the minority in this regard. I dislike how little the course material emphasizes proofs, which was a big deal with my high school professor. I generally appreciate understanding a formula or theorem before applying it, but a quick &amp;ldquo;this proof is too beyond the scope of this course&amp;rdquo; would be nicer than Christian&amp;rsquo;s usual &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re not going to prove it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the first midterm, the panic has set in, and the class has formed a study group. I attended one of the meetings so I could meet some of my classmates (lame haha) and it was honestly pretty chill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall rating:&lt;/strong> 3.5 stars.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="university-honors-courses">University Honors Courses&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am in the Honors College within UMD, in the program called &amp;ldquo;University Honors&amp;rdquo;. It is a two-year program where we can pick classes from predetermined thematic clusters. I picked the 238 series, which goes in-depth about deliberation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hnuh-238a---deliberating-democracy">HNUH 238A - Deliberating Democracy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This course is named &amp;ldquo;Deliberating Democracy&amp;rdquo;, where we dive deep about deliberation in society: how do we talk to one another about controversial issues, and how can we make them productive and efficient? Every week begins with multiple readings, where we analyze argumentative structure (e.g., Toulmin Model of Argumentation), deliberative techniques, social issues, and more. On Wednesdays, different groups engage in deliberation about a topic, which we use to write a report and submit by the end of the week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The class is led by three people: Dr. Shawn Perry-Giles (the professor), Matthew Salzano (TA #1), and Taylor Hourigan (TA #2). Course material is very political, ranging from gun control to abortion to free speech. I think the concept of the class is very solid: allow people to engage in good and effective deliberation so people can listen to other viewpoints and get things done. However, the class is taught through a very liberal lens, where a lot of what I would consider disputable claims are taken to be true. I think this kind of contradicts the notion of open-mindedness that good deliberation is supposed to inculcate. Readings can be pretty dull at times, but I think it is nice that different articles sometimes contain opposing ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the weekly deliberations, my group and I deliberate about a given topic. There are three roles, including a facilitator (who governs and directs the conversation, asks questions, passes the mic, etc.), report lead, and note taker. Our conversations are usually pretty engaging, but it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a group consensus that we&amp;rsquo;re doing it to get it done. On Sunday, we usually try to finish the report. Jason (who&amp;rsquo;s also in my group) and I carry the group in writing the report, as we are the ones usually proofreading and shortening the page count to the acceptable amount.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assignments are pretty easy, and the grading is quite lenient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall rating:&lt;/strong> 2.5 stars.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hnuh-100---honors-seminar">HNUH 100 - Honors Seminar&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the University Honor&amp;rsquo;s introductory seminar. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially like high school homeroom. It&amp;rsquo;s an introduction to the school and the honors program. The goal is to prepare you for the next four years. It meets only once a week and is only 1 credit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We go over school events, writing resumes, introduction to the program— all the uninspiring stuff. My professor is very nice (Prof. Erica Smith), but it is truly hard to take the class seriously. It is supposed to be an easier and friendlier class, which it is, but the classroom dynamic is pretty poor and nobody wants to be there. Good thing it only meets once a week. Assignments are quick and easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall rating:&lt;/strong> 2 stars&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="umd-life">UMD Life&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20210930_203918-min.jpg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20210930_203918-min_hu1faea9e5e8e8f525f9f1c77e83222142_760214_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20210930_203918-min_hu1faea9e5e8e8f525f9f1c77e83222142_760214_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Lantern Festival with the Vietnamese Student Association"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dormitories">Dormitories&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you know, I got extremely lucky being able to reside at Pyon-Chen Hall. I have been in a few of the other dormitories, and I will rank them below. This is not an exhaustive list; there are many dormitories I haven&amp;rsquo;t stepped foot in yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="6-ellicott">6. Ellicott&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Christina, Steph, and Rajit live here. The rooms are pretty small, the bathrooms suck, and there is no A/C. The hallways are grim and kind of ugly, there are roaches and bugs in the basement, and people do not seem to enjoy the building very much. It is right across the diner if there is one good thing to say. Not great.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="5-hagerstown">5. Hagerstown&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Jason Luo and Daniel live here. No A/C and very similar looking to La Plata and Ellicott. Their rooms are actually kind of spacious, at least better than Ellicott and La Plata. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that hot when I went here, so I had a relatively pleasant time hanging out with my friends. I did not go to the bathroom, but I imagine it&amp;rsquo;s like your average communal bathroom. Not terrible, but not great either.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="4-cumberland-hall">4. Cumberland Hall&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Brian and Alan live here. It has A/C in the rooms, the hallways are kind of grim, and the bathrooms are pretty low-tier. The common area is right out the elevator instead of another room, so they aren&amp;rsquo;t as good as La Plata. The rooms are a bit musty and small, but overall, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have any problems living here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-la-plata-hall">3. La Plata Hall&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Yuri, Dong, and Alex live here. It has A/C in the dorm rooms, but not in many of the other parts of the building. The hallways are relatively narrow, the bathrooms are okay, and the wall colors are not particularly nice. The rooms are kind of small, and you can visibly see pipes above your head. The common rooms are pretty comfortable and nice to hang out in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-anne-arundel-hall">2. Anne Arundel Hall&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dheeraj lives in this hall, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been there once. It feels like a bedroom, with carpeted floors, an angled ceiling, and brown bed frames. It&amp;rsquo;s more spacious than the other halls I&amp;rsquo;ve been in. It has A/C as well. Good first impressions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0595.jpg"
width="1699"
height="1274"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0595_hu9e2349326b7c590da227e31c0dc7a4d6_339415_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0595_hu9e2349326b7c590da227e31c0dc7a4d6_339415_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Anne Arundel Hall"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-pyon-chen-hall">1. Pyon-Chen Hall&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Obviously, the one I am in is the best. There are 6 floors in this building, each one identical to the next. There is a left and a right wing, which mirror one another, with 7 communal private (everyone shares, but each bathroom is private) bathrooms each. The rooms themselves are quite spacious, with A/C, black and wooden floors, white walls, and 2 Twin XL beds. There is an open closet, dresser, and table as well. There is one relatively small, tall, rectangular window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a very comfortable living experience. Many people from other dorms visit their friends here, as there are many nice study rooms, and each dorm room has plenty of space for multiple people to hang out in. The bathrooms are miles better than the other dorms; you don&amp;rsquo;t have to risk being seen naked by your neighbors; you can spend as long as you want sitting on the toilet; the shower heads actually have decent water pressure. I am very privileged, as you can see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Living with Jason has been pretty fun. We have gotten significantly closer, spending late nights chatting about stupid things, making inappropriate and lame jokes, and just generally spending most of our time together. Love to Mr. Liu from me &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephanie pretty much spends most of her time here, arriving at 4 pm and leaving at 11 or 12 pm. Many of of our other friends come pretty often, either to hang out or to shower, and Jason and I are happy to lend a hand to anyone. It&amp;rsquo;s been pretty great. That&amp;rsquo;s why our dorm gets the #1 ranking.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="miscellaneous">Miscellaneous&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The apartments we went to off-campus are quite deluxe. With monthly fees less than those of on-campus residence halls, it seems like a steal. However, you can be pretty far from your classes, have to buy your own groceries, and will have fewer chances to see your friends. It&amp;rsquo;s however you make it. But the buildings themselves have excellent common areas, study rooms, and layout. The rooms feel like upgraded hotels. I&amp;rsquo;ll get one&amp;hellip;maybe someday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also heard Prince Frederick is really good, perhaps better than Pyon-Chen. It&amp;rsquo;s where the ACES Honors people live. I will definitely need to check it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dining-hall-experience">Dining Hall Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are three dining halls on campus: Ellicott Dining, 251 North (Denton), and the South Campus Dining. I live a minute away from Ellicott dining, so I go there most of the time. All of the dining halls are pretty decent, with a large selection of food, ranging from pasta to tacos to ramen. There is a vegan section, a salad bar with greens and fruit, and a pizza place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My meals are generally hit or miss, but the misses aren&amp;rsquo;t too bad. I often go for the &amp;ldquo;Cluckers&amp;rdquo; restaurant in Ellicott, where I fill my plate with some pasta, greens, one piece of meat, and some form of rice. The mac &amp;amp; cheese is good, the quesadillas are good, and the tacos are pretty excellent. The breakfast food is usually pretty sad, and each day&amp;rsquo;s choices are always the same. The diner offers eggs, bacon, sad potatoes, sometimes okay hash browns, and usually pretty bland and sad pancakes. There are waffle machines if you are into that. Dessert is typically pretty static: cakes, pies, cookies, and the soft-serve machine. The types of cakes and pies usually rotate, and they are pretty hit or miss, but I usually go for the soft-serve anyway. I recommend you stay health-conscious, unlike me 😅.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://www.uniquevenues.com/sites/uniquevenues.com/files/imagecache/venue_flexslider_2018/venues/slideshow/DSC_6497.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Ellicott Dining Hall"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Ellicott Dining Hall&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lunch and dinner are usually pretty solid, though. However, on weekends, the breakfast food generally becomes lunch food, since students wake up late (obviously for good reason). The food choices of each dining hall are relatively similar, but I think Ellicott is still the best. It has a nice layout with cute neon signs, which overrules the kind of boring and plain layouts of 251 and South Campus. However, the seating arrangement is much more cramped and structured, compared to the open seating of 251 and South Campus. Furthermore, my friends rave over 251 for their cheesy garlic bread, so take that for what it&amp;rsquo;s worth. Overall, the food has exceeded expectations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="partying-environment">Partying Environment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This portion is a detailed experience about a dream I had a few days ago, and nothing more. Think about it like your favorite fiction book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UMD isn&amp;rsquo;t as big of a party school as I expected it to be. There are likely a lot, but my connections are pretty limited and I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly like the big and loud ones. From what I heard from friends, parties are much more rampant and easy to find, but this could be the result of the smaller population of private schools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t go into more detail, as it is something you should find out naturally. Also, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get a mark on my record. Self-preservation is important.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="eppley-recreation-center">Eppley Recreation Center&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is the main rec center for everybody. It&amp;rsquo;s a two-minute walk from Pyon-Chen Hall, making it very convenient to exercise. There are 5 basketball courts, one gym with multiple rooms, and a pool in the basement. Basketball can be pretty sweaty, depending on who you play with. The courts are generally packed, and you have to wait your turn to play. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many opportunities to casually play ball with your friends unless you go super early or super late. Furthermore, the volleyball players share the courts, making it kind of cramped and pretty annoying, as you can get sucker-punched by a flying ball while trying to get that behind-the-back dunk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://campusrecmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/16018483608_ef1a24953e_z.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Epply Recreational Center Gym"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Epply Recreational Center Gym&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The gym is big, but then again, there are 40k undergrads at UMD. It is packed in the evening, but not unreasonably so. You can navigate your way through most equipment and the bench without much waiting. There are a lot of machines, a dinky little track, and many weights. It is a nice gym.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pool is also pretty nice. It closes earlier than the rest of the gym (at 10:00 pm). There are two pools you can swim in, but unfortunately, both are less than 25m long. Club swim takes up one of the pools at a set time, so plan wisely. Every time I&amp;rsquo;ve gone, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to get a line to myself. The locker room is a good place to shower, mostly if you live in the lesser dorms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="restaurants-and-shopping">Restaurants and Shopping&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a nice shopping center right outside the entrance of the university, with a Target, Chipotle, Kung-Fu Tea, CVS, barbershop, and more. It&amp;rsquo;s a quaint place to buy a couple of groceries or to eat out with friends. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a few late-night journeys to McDonald&amp;rsquo;s because the one thing you crave at 3 am is a box of chicken nuggets. The school is surrounded by places to buy food, so it won&amp;rsquo;t be hard grabbing a bite at the restaurant of your choice. My biggest gripe is that there is no Asian Supermarket nearby. What a shame.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20211002_135457-min.jpg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20211002_135457-min_huc15c9556e81588cd0c04a02a57fbecab_727230_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20211002_135457-min_huc15c9556e81588cd0c04a02a57fbecab_727230_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Ramen at Kangnam College Park"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On-campus also has a few restaurants, primarily at STAMP, with a Subway, Chick-Fil-A, Quickway, and more. You can use dining dollars there, which is pretty cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="adele-h-stamp-union">Adele H. Stamp Union&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Stamp Union (Stamp for short), is the community center for UMD students. Inside are many open seating areas, the food court, a bowling alley, arcade, miniature movie theater, convenience store, UMD gear shop, and large rooms for clubs (e.g., TASA, CSA). It is a nice area to get food, grab ice cream, or just hang out. I watched A Quiet Place 2 there, which was a pretty nice experience. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a charming place to go to hang out with your friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://universityofmaryland.myuvn.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/39/2018/12/TheStampAtNight.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="STAMP Union"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>STAMP Union&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="freshman-flu">Freshman Flu&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Almost everyone in my friend group got sick one after another. During a time with COVID, that&amp;rsquo;s not particularly confidence-inspiring. Good thing is that none of us got COVID. Bad thing, we all probably got each other sick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended up getting strep throat, probably a fever, and severe cough. Most of my friends did as well, and some are still sick. My friends at other schools also got sick. Being around a lot of people in a new environment obviously explains the cause, so be prepared. Bring cough drops, cold medication, and whatnot. It&amp;rsquo;s better to be prepared, cause you are most definitely going to get sick within the first month.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="memorable-moments">Memorable Moments&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-jumping-into-mckeldin-mall-with-jason">1. Jumping into McKeldin Mall with Jason&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At 3:30 am on October 2, 2021, Jason Liu and Eric Chen jumped into the pool at McKeldin Mall. A series of unfortunate events transpired the night of, and Eric was not feeling too well. The two ventured on a walk around campus, with Jason consoling Eric over his devastation. Suddenly, Eric considered the possibility that one day he and Jason and friends should go swimming in the pool in the middle of the night. Jason concurred, saying that it was a marvelous idea. As the two left, Eric had a eureka moment. He was having a bad night and thought there was nothing to lose, asking Jason, &amp;ldquo;Do you want to jump in right now?&amp;rdquo; Jason, daring as one can possibly be, agreed with a wide smile on his face. The two jumped into the shallow, frigid waters of McKeldin, recording their silly antics on their decrepit smartphones and posting the videos on social media. It was a night to remember.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-watching-squid-game">2. Watching Squid Game&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before Squid Game, I had never watched a K-Drama before. The closest I ever got to watching a K-Drama was by watching Parasite at Yuri&amp;rsquo;s birthday party. But Steph kept pushing our friend group, telling us that we must watch the show that was dominating social media and Netflix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yuri, Christina, Jason, Steph, and I spent three late nights riding an emotional roller coaster on Jason&amp;rsquo;s 34-inch widescreen monitor. The show was great— filled with stakes, family issues, friendship, and more. I thoroughly enjoyed the show, despite being slightly disappointed at a somewhat lackluster ending. I do not deal well with anything remotely scary or stressful, and this show was both. Generally, I avoid watching strenuous and tense shows, as my heart generally can&amp;rsquo;t keep up. Watching with friends helped ease me up, and it ended up being one of the more fun experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had on campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend you to watch the show if you somehow haven&amp;rsquo;t already. I am not a TV show or movie connoisseur, so I will not be reviewing it, unfortunately. I apologize for any inconvenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-finishing-steins-gate">3. Finishing Stein&amp;rsquo;s Gate&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Fantastic Four— Yuri, Christina, Jason, and I— began watching Stein&amp;rsquo;s Gate sometime in June or July during this summer. By the start of school, we probably weren&amp;rsquo;t even halfway finished. Before school started, we convened on Zoom and watched a variety of movies, like Howl&amp;rsquo;s Moving Castle and The Shawshank Redemption. It was a way for us to propel our budding group synergy and team superpowers; unfortunately, we were really bad at finding nights to watch Stein&amp;rsquo;s Gate, so we decided to finish it when the school year commenced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20210901_215756.jpg"
width="956"
height="1274"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20210901_215756_hu7565fac8eb6f8ada7a813b40e24927b6_145597_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20210901_215756_hu7565fac8eb6f8ada7a813b40e24927b6_145597_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Jason and Yuri preparing for Stein&amp;rsquo;s Gate"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a lot of fun spending time with my fellow superheroes, making fun of Okabe&amp;rsquo;s weird facial expressions and Feyris&amp;rsquo;s cutesy speech tick in the early AMs. Yuri and Christina would often be too exhausted to go back to their dorms at 4 am and would spend the night at Pyon-Chen, either sleeping on the floor like psychos or forcing me to get closey-feely with Jason. I honestly need to re-watch the show at some point, because so much time spanned in between each watching session that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t feel the severity of each scene. Fortunately, the show is littered with confusing time travel, gender mix-ups, and uncomfortable relationships, perfect things for us to joke about. I still thoroughly enjoyed it, but the time spent with those 3 losers was what made it a blast.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-getting-ears-pierced">4. Getting Ears Pierced&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I made a promise to Yuri and Christina in the summer. They proposed the idea of me getting my ears pierced. At the time, I was hesitant to agree and relatively against it. I replied with an &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it if Jason does it&amp;rdquo;, assuming that Jason would decline on my behalf. Unfortunately, Jason was a wilder person than I imagined and immediately agreed, burdening me with a curse I bestowed upon myself. After months of stalling, the four of us visited Red Octopus Tattoos to get our ears pierced— Yuri and Christina getting their second, and Jason and I getting our first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The piercing itself only took a minute max. They cleaned my ears, poked two holes, and it was over. It was mildly painful and definitely less painful than I expected, which was a surprise. Now, my ears and decorated with shiny diamonds, making me the most fashionable man on this planet. Just kidding. Even though Yuri and Christina think it is glamorous, I feel kind of like an idiot for wearing them. I am the furthest thing from a &amp;ldquo;bad boy&amp;rdquo; as you can possibly imagine. The experience afterward has been pretty good. We surprised Steph, Alan, and Brian later that day. The first few nights were terrible, as I could not sleep in my desired position because of the piercings, leading to poor sleep quality. It is better now, but still slightly uncomfortable. Spraying my ears with cleaning solution has not been a hassle at all, but it leaves my earholes pretty itchy, probably from the salt crystallizing around the earring. But overall, I am glad I got them pierced. Life is too short for me to not experiment. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try going bald for a bit or dying my hair neon yellow. Who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="5-invading-clarice-at-3-am">5. Invading Clarice at 3 A.M.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is allegedly true. Maybe it was a dream. I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yuri invited me and Jason to go on a panic walk, as she had an exam the next day. We walked in silence, ending up at Clarice around 3 in the morning (haha, again). In the dim glow of the moon, my mischievous and immature self decided to check if each door was open, while Jason and Yuri enjoyed the beauty of the building&amp;rsquo;s architecture and the crisp air of the night. After checking dozens of doors to no avail, I was crushed. On our way back to our dorms, I decided to check one more door. I pulled with hesitation, expecting nothing but disappointment, but the door opened. It was Christmas. We excitedly opened the door and explored the tall and empty music building. What daring students!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0627-min.jpg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0627-min_hu7480bbe6558c7dfc5c35911ea769dd6d_920770_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/IMG_0627-min_hu7480bbe6558c7dfc5c35911ea769dd6d_920770_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Outside Clarice Center for the Performing Arts"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="clubs">Clubs&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Clubs don&amp;rsquo;t start for a while after school starts. The First-Look Fair—UMD&amp;rsquo;s club fair—happened almost a month after classes began. The large selection of clubs would satisfy any diehard artist, passionate engineer, or political fanatic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went to a lot of On-Board Meetings (OBMs), and I can give you some thoughts about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students-for-the-exploration-of-development-of-space-seds">Students for the Exploration of Development of Space (SEDS)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This club is self-explanatory. It focuses on space-related exploration, where club members split up into groups and focus on one engineering or educational task for the duration of the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I joined relatively late— a week or two after the first OBM. Interested in the premise of a liquid rocket, I went to the second introductory meeting about the engineering that goes into it. It was more of a lecture, as the two sub-team captains began describing the details of propellant pressure, tank wall thickness, and operating stress. This went way over my head, as I have minimum—almost zero—engineering experience. However, I liked that the team went straight to business, which made me keen about coming back the following week. At the end of the OBM, I asked it was okay that I did not understand anything, and the captains quelled my fear by saying that it was okay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later that day, I put the liquid rocket team as my first preference for the club, over nanosatellites or the BBP (don&amp;rsquo;t even know what that is). Somehow, I got my first choice, so I will be part of the liquid rocket team for this semester. I should beef up on the knowledge necessary for the club, and I am optimistic about the places this club will take me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="terrapin-racing">Terrapin Racing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This club focuses on designing one formula racecar, electric formula racecar, and one off-road Baja racecar for the to compete in collegiate racing competitions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This club has left the strongest impression on me so far. I signed up for the club at the FLF, but they never got back to me. I asked my friend, Rajit, who had joined the club beforehand, whether I could tag along with him to a meeting. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about formula cars, but it sounded really interesting and I was willing to give the club a shot. Rajit introduced me to the captain, who gave me a briefing about the team and project teams. Cap told me that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much space left on the team, and I should try next semester when a new wave of people join. But right as he said that the composites team lead came over and said he needed people for the composites team. Given no other choice, I followed him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The composites team focuses on building the composite parts on the formula car, like the body, side panels, and more. Instead of giving me a lecture on what the team does or what my responsibilities as a team member were, the team lead, Aly, put me straight to work. I helped the other lead, Max, with cutting the carbon fiber fabric for the monocoque of the car. On the first day, I spent 3 hours there, cutting fabric, infusing the carbon fiber with epoxy and hardener, and molding the fabric over the male monocoque mold. I felt useful for once, and despite the relatively menial tasks I was asked to do, was 100% set on coming to the next meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20211016_123440-min.jpg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20211016_123440-min_hu3369e670161579e3e397076833949b65_1201370_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/two-months-at-umd/20211016_123440-min_hu3369e670161579e3e397076833949b65_1201370_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Carbon Fiber Monocoque! So beautiful before we had to destroy it&amp;hellip;"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been to three meetings so far, and it has been excellent. Although not directly learning about how things work, I have picked up bits and pieces of information along the way. Each meeting has been pretty (un)eventful, and I have done something different every time. Our first mold was completely unsuccessful, as the carbon fiber we attached to the mold wouldn&amp;rsquo;t separate, as the Gelcoat layer underneath did not adhere to the fabric properly. We were forced to cut it and painstakingly rip off each piece, which took many hours. After kind of ruining the foam mold (which cost upwards of 6 grand), we were forced to put Bondo (an automotive body filler) over the cracks and joints and sand them down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of fun talking to the group members: Hugo, Max, Aly, Ryan, Samantha, and Nick. We&amp;rsquo;ve joked around about our favorite movies, hobbies, etc., and I actually feel as if I am a part of a team. I think I can accomplish a lot as part of the team. Even with the large time commitment, I think it will be worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bit-camp">Bit Camp&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This club hosts a large hackathon at the end of each school year, called Bit Camp. I attended the OBM, which went into detail about the sub-teams, organization, and goals. When I heard about the tech team, I wanted in. The tech team works on the web and phone apps and backend design. When I saw that they use AWS for a lot of their work, I knew that this would be a golden opportunity for me to learn a lot by putting my skills to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have never worked collaboratively with someone on a coding project before, and this seems like a perfect solution to my dilemma. Unfortunately, the team is relatively selective and requires an application. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience with a lot of things, and there is a good chance I am not selected. I am still hopeful, and I want to get in. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="college-park-student-investment-group">College Park Student Investment Group&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This team teaches investment-related anything. Despite my genius, I am relatively financially illiterate. I need to learn finance, which is why I decided to join this club.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went to one meeting, which dived into details about the fundamental analysis of the stock market. It was alright, maybe a bit uninspiring. There were two presentations going on in the same room, where one of the presenters was at least twice as loud as the other. I was struggling to hear what my presenter was saying, but I got the gist of it. I did learn quite a bit about fundamental analysis, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much more effective this is compared to learning the content online. The in-personness of the club is motivation to keep learning, however. I will probably be attending this club for purely informational reasons, but perhaps the events will be worth going to. We shall see.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startup-shell">Startup Shell&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this club, but I applied to it nonetheless. I believe it has to do with startups (haha), and it seems pretty exclusive and cool. I have a virtual interview with the captain tomorrow; wish me luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I had my interview already. Kind of. I showed up at the interview time; no one was there. I emailed them afterward asking about what I should do, with no response. My disappointment is immeasurable and my day is ruined.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="terrapin-rockets">Terrapin Rockets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This club does exactly as its name suggests. The team builds a rocket and enters competitions. Can&amp;rsquo;t get cooler than that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went to the first General Board Meeting (GBM), which went into detail about the events planned and logistics of entering competitions. As a complete noob, I found it difficult to understand what was going on, as the meeting content seemed directed to people who were familiar with the club. The captains were already talking about test launches, working on draft schematics and CAD models for different teams, and competition guidelines, and I was just sitting there confused out of my mind. I thought it would crystallize later on, but the second GBM was canceled, leaving me in the dark. If I had been inspired by the first meeting, I would definitely have put in the effort to learn what was going on, but I had pretty much lost interest at that point. Considering how big of an astronomy nerd I am, that&amp;rsquo;s kind of sad. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the club is great and will accomplish many great things, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s for me, at least for this semester. I will try again next semester or next year, for sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bigthnk-ai">BigTh!nk AI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The club specializes in teaching AI and machine learning. I do not have much experience with AI and decided to see what it was like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I joined the pyoneers team, which is the entry-level introductory group that focuses on the basics. In the first meeting, the captains went over Pandas DataFrames, which I already know a little bit about, as I did a machine learning internship before my senior year in high school. It was moderately useful and well explained. The team doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel cohesive but I think it is a good place to learn about AI if that is something that truly interests you. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I will keep going, but if I do, it will be for learning purposes only— I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on committing a lot of time to this organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clubs that didn&amp;rsquo;t follow up after the first-look fair, why? You need new members. I want to be one. Send me an email next time, please. Also, I hate how every club uses a different platform of communication. I have to juggle between GroupMe, Slack, Discord, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to get organized.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a pretty positive experience so far. Some clubs I hope to look into at some point:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Geology Club&lt;/li>
&lt;li>G-Girls and the Wasabi Boyz (Asian pop dance group)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gaming Symphony Orchestra&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ultimate Frisbee Team&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Beware of clubs that seem good on the surface&amp;hellip;some of the FLF people looked super unenthusiastic about their own club. Use your instinct to filter out the ones that are just for people to boost their resumes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="goals">Goals&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post would be meaningless if I did not outline a few goals I have for my first year at college.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-straight-as">Get Straight A&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>More like a pipe dream— it&amp;rsquo;s almost certainly not happening, but I can dream on. I feel like I have a head start compared to most people at this school, but I am also incredibly lazy and unfocused most of the time. At least, I will try my hardest to do well on every exam and complete my homework on time, with less procrastination than I did in high school. If I fail a class, nobody will give a 💩 but me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I already did poorly on a CMSC 216 exam, but I still have hope. Let&amp;rsquo;s get this bread.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="find-a-club-i-am-passionate-about">Find a club I am passionate about&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I mean, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t? We&amp;rsquo;re still in the entry phases, so I have a lot of exploring to do. My life practically revolved around extracurriculars in high school, like Debate Team and Science Bowl. I want to find something I can pour my heart into. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to just attend meetings and feel like a foreigner visiting a new country. I want to get my nails dirty, heart pumping, and brain racing. The one club that seems pretty promising right now is Bit Camp, but I still have faith in the rocket and engineering clubs.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: It&amp;rsquo;s been so long since I started writing this post, so things have changed a bit. I already have some top contenders for this goal! Look above at the &amp;ldquo;Clubs&amp;rdquo; section for more detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="make-new-friends">Make new friends&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have gotten too comfortable with people I already know. That&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing in and of itself; I love the current friends I have, but that has prevented me from exploring the seas. I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on an island— a great island, mind you— but there is way more to explore. I hope clubs will be an entry point for me to develop long-lasting friendships. I have made a couple of acquaintances and a few friends, but I still mostly hang out with my middle and high school friends. It&amp;rsquo;s time to widen the circle a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-an-internship">Get an Internship&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t want an internship? As a computer engineering/comp sci student, I really should get one this summer. Not only will it provide me with skills in the industry, but it can also probably help me pay off my loans and buy a bunch of useless crap that I want. I want to see what it&amp;rsquo;s like to work as a small part of something huge, and I intend to find an internship of my liking. I would say my #1 option would be Amazon right now, but I&amp;rsquo;m a long ways to go. Wish me luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-a-girlfriend">Get a girlfriend&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Self-explanatory.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="read-a-textbook-of-all-the-basic-sciences">Read a textbook of all the basic sciences&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My goal for a &lt;em>long time&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s one of my longer-term and incredibly ambitious goals, and I hope I can fulfill it. I absolutely love learning, and it already hurts me to not be able to major in everything. I want general knowledge about all the sciences, and I will do my best to read a textbook of all of them: Chemistry, Earth Science, Astronomy, Biology, and Physics. I&amp;rsquo;m partially done, but there is a long way to go. I also intend on going deeper into some subjects, like Organic Chemistry, Astrophysics, Quantum, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="start-new-projects">Start new projects&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I often get too lazy to actively work on projects. When I learned Django for the first time, I spent weeks on that and then got burned out. I need to continuously push and learn new things, whether it be learning a computer science framework or engineering tool, reading a book, becoming financially literate. I need to get off my lazy bum and push. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to start tomorrow. No, it &lt;em>&lt;strong>must&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> start tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="continue-playing-violin">Continue playing violin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing violin for a long time. Too long. It would be a real shame if I just dropped the ball now and gave up. Ever since I got on campus, I&amp;rsquo;ve played violin at least once a week. Am I proud of doing the bare minimum? No. But it is something I should preserve, and I should not waste my talent (loosely speaking). I want to learn at least a few pieces over the school year. Let&amp;rsquo;s get this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="everything-else">Everything else&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I think long-term goals are not effective for me, at least. Too many variables change all the time, and the abstractness of most long-term goals is not enough to motivate me. If I cannot even visualize where the finish line is, then I will not feel bad not achieving something. I will work on my short-term goals for now. If anything else pops up, I will let my fans know. Keep me honest.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="tips">Tips&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-find-a-tasks-app">1. Find a tasks app&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You should probably have one already, but get one if you don&amp;rsquo;t. Organization is key, and if you fail a course, that&amp;rsquo;s on you and nobody else, because the money is coming out of your pocket. I personally recommend &lt;a class="link" href="https://ticktick.com/?language=en_US" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>TickTick&lt;/a>, which is available on all platforms. Put all your assignments and to-do things, and organize them by when they&amp;rsquo;re due. It&amp;rsquo;s been mightily helpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-start-planning-out-your-schedule-for-the-rest-of-college">2. Start planning out your schedule for the rest of college&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can find a four-year plan for your major online. It helps to have a mental plan of what requirements you need to complete by when, the prerequisites for each course you take, and when the best time to take a gen-ed is. It&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that you will follow through with the first draft, but it is required for your mandatory advising and will allow you to visualize what needs to get done when. A basic skeleton is better than a pile of bones.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-get-started-on-internships-and-research-early">3. Get started on internships and research early&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a career fair at the end of the first month of school. You should attend to see if you can find anything interesting and stem from there. Look online for possible internships, and start applying early! You don&amp;rsquo;t want to get to a point where all applications are closed. You&amp;rsquo;ll be sad, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sad, everyone will be sad. Plan out what you want, and go for it. The more, the better. This means writing a good resume. There are a lot of good resources online for how to craft one. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience; most people don&amp;rsquo;t, and you can still have a better resume than someone more accomplished than you if you know what you are doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-get-a-water-boiler">4. Get a water boiler&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the rainy days where you only have time for ramen. Get a fridge, too. For the days where you wake up 15 minutes before class starts and you have no time to visit the diner. *Cough cough* Jason.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="5-bring-tupperware">5. Bring Tupperware&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dining halls don&amp;rsquo;t let you take food out&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not telling you to circumvent rules. That would be ridiculous! Inconceivable, you might say!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="6-get-a-credit-card">6. Get a credit card&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>College is a good time to build credit. You won&amp;rsquo;t need to pay fees if you spend responsibly, and chances are, it&amp;rsquo;ll help you when you start getting the big bucks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="7-dont-put-off-your-debts">7. Don&amp;rsquo;t put off your debts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get caught up and school and forget that you are taking out loans. You should build a strategy now on your repayment scheme, whether it applies now or four years from now. If you exit college with crippling debt because of ignorance, that&amp;rsquo;s on you. Start learning financial basics and figure out the easiest way for you to pay off your loans. If you get started immediately, you could save future you from a nasty migraine. Take finance classes! Find an investment or finance club to join! Good luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="8-meet-new-people">8. Meet new people&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Lucky number 8, taken from Jason. Even though this is pretty obvious, really go and do it. A lot of you will go to a new school where you might only know a few kids from your county if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky. You should try to meet people online before you even arrive on campus. Plan some things to do in the first few days. Don&amp;rsquo;t end up sulking alone, watching anime, or playing video games in your dorm room. Go to orientation or welcoming events. As lame as they can be, they are still good ways to find new friends. Even though I am going to a school with a lot of kids from my high school, it&amp;rsquo;s still a blessing and a curse. I get to hang out with people I&amp;rsquo;ve built relationships with over the last 4-7 years, it&amp;rsquo;s halted my search for new ones. Although I spent the first month almost exclusively spending time with people I already knew, I have been trying to improve. I&amp;rsquo;ve attended a dozen clubs, hoping to find people to connect with. I am already excited to be part of some clubs, and I think friendships will only be incidental from then. But I encourage you to be better than me. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid, there is literally nothing to lose.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="conclusion-1">Conclusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
When I got rejected from my top choices for college, I was crushed. It was a huge hit on my self-esteem. I thought I wasn't good enough, smart enough, and didn't try hard enough. I was afraid I disappointed my parents by wasting their efforts and money. I was sad that I made my sister and her friends spend hours helping me on my essays, only to be greeted by the hand of rejection. But after being on campus, I know now that those fears were unjustified. Sure, I might not have had fruitful results, but I am still on a path where I believe I can succeed. I'm around people I like and in an environment that still pushes me to work hard. As long as you still have the drive, those variables won't change.
&lt;p>School is only a stepping stone to your future. Looking back in time, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t even consider it to be in the top 10 most important events of your life. The university you attended was &lt;em>not&lt;/em> the one factor that led to your success, or your failure. You can find that anywhere, as long as you have the will to pursue what you are looking for in life. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed if you didn&amp;rsquo;t get into your top college. Those feelings are still justified, but you truly will be okay. I am lucky in the sense that UMD is excellent for my major, but I firmly believe that a person working extremely hard at a lower-tier college can be massively more successful than the average student at Harvard or MIT. It&amp;rsquo;s the effort that makes it count.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should still try as hard as you can on college applications. If you can go to a better school, why not? But if you don&amp;rsquo;t get in, that&amp;rsquo;s okay too. I have been loving it here so far, just like my sister said. I like my friends, my clubs, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited for the courses in the upcoming semesters. My classes are easy enough to the point where it gives me the time to do what I want. I have surprised myself with an improving work ethic, and I think I will go far here. But the road ahead will be defined by the work I am willing to put in. Hopefully, I don&amp;rsquo;t reach a cliff. That would be bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The way to get started is to quit talking and begin doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>-Walt Disney&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="list-of-visitors-so-far">List of visitors so far:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bumjin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ethan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Iris&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shariar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Esther&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You guys are the best 😘.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Favorite Android Applications!</title><link>https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-android-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-android-applications/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-android-applications/android.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post My Favorite Android Applications!" />&lt;p>Android has some fantastic and unique apps, and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a couple of my favorites. This blog post was influenced by the one and only Eli Qian. You can find the post about his iPhone setup &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.eliqian.com/post/iphone-home-screen-setup" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the apps I will talk about are not from the Google Play Store. This is generally because they might not be able to survive there and rely on you to sideload them. However, this is a very simple task on Android, which is one reason I prefer it over iOS. Be careful with downloading malicious apps as they will likely steal your data or mess up your device in some way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can sideload apps that would otherwise cost money on the Google Play Store. I have done this with a couple of apps, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really recommend it. This is because they will not get automatic updates and do not support the developer. However, if you make the argument that you will patronize the creator when you are financially capable of doing so, I can get behind that. I do pay for 99% of my apps, so don&amp;rsquo;t arrest me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A general tip: If you do use Reddit, join the subreddit for the indie apps on your phone. It will let you know about features coming down the line, and you can submit bugs or request features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Note: Most of these apps are also available on iOS. Just search for them in the App Store and see if they exist.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="general-apps">General Apps&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="google-opinion-rewards-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Google Opinion Rewards   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Every Android user should have this app. Google Opinion Rewards is a rewards-based program by Google. All you need to do is answer the surveys it gives you and you will be able to receive rewards in the form of your Google Play Balance. Surveys will pop up every few days or so based on your activity on your phone. Questions range from &amp;ldquo;Have you been to &lt;em>this place&lt;/em> recently&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Have you searched for this term using Google Assistant?&amp;rdquo;. They take less than a minute, and rewards will range from 10 cents to a dollar. The more questions you answer (based on your answers to previous questions), the more money you earn. I&amp;rsquo;ve probably amassed over $20 in total in less than two years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve used the money to buy apps. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason for you not to get it. I believe iOS also has this app, where you can earn some money towards PayPal instead, which is kinda cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="google-keep-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Google Keep   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Good for jotting down a couple of notes. I use it for writing down important things and saving URLs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="google-photos-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Google Photos   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It backs up your photos and allows you to sync photos across devices. Either get free 1080p unlimited or have each picture contribute to your 15GB limit. Every phone user (iOS or Android) should have this app. You can also share albums with friends and family.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-vancedhttpsvancedappcom-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">&lt;a class="link" href="https://vancedapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Youtube Vanced&lt;/a>   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is by far my favorite app. It&amp;rsquo;s a side-loaded YouTube alternative that offers different themes, ad-free playback, and SponsorBlock. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially Youtube Premium with more customization. The app has user-login through MicroG, a Google Play Services mod. SponsorBlock allows you to skip pesky portions of YouTube videos, like intros, sponsored messages, and empty silence. I was skeptical of it at first, but it actually works very well. As someone who watches YouTube a ton, this app is literally a blessing from above. Vanced also has automatic updates through their Vanced manager, which allows you to update MicroG, YT Vanced, but also YT Music Vanced, which is essentially free YouTube Music (albeit, no download capabilities). No hassle and easy updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="weather-timeline-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">Weather Timeline   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This app was discontinued as the developer, Sam Ruston, couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up with the Weather API fees. The app was supposed to be rereleased as it was purchased by MyRadar, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really see that happening any time soon. You can currently sideload it if you would like, but you won&amp;rsquo;t get any app updates. I really like this weather app, due to its simplicity and design. It has minute-to-minute precipitation, rain and snow notifications, and an overall pleasing look. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how good its accuracy is, but the app design is why I continue to use it. It&amp;rsquo;s overall an excellent weather app, and I highly recommend it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://www.androidsis.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/weather-timeline.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of adroidsis.com"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of adroidsis.com&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ticktick-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">TickTick   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The to-do list app in my life. It&amp;rsquo;s very good for managing tasks and has a clean design. It will automatically schedule tasks with keywords, like &amp;ldquo;tomorrow,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;next week,&amp;rdquo; etc. Its free version is actually good enough for me. Premium features include calendar integration, calendar view, smart lists, and more. It&amp;rsquo;s $2.99 / M or $27.99 / Y. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried Google tasks and Todoist, but TickTick is just better.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tachiyomihttpstachiyomiorg-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">&lt;a class="link" href="https://tachiyomi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Tachiyomi&lt;/a>   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The best app for the manga reader in your life. That&amp;rsquo;s not me, but this app is really good. It has a clean design and dozens of manga sources available, from NSFW stuff to your normal stuff. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t use it much, it is riddled with convenient features and gives you access to things you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to read otherwise. It is a sideloaded app (also indie), and you can find it &lt;a class="link" href="https://tachiyomi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>here&lt;/a>. Thank you to Maxwell Zhang for telling me about this app.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="duolingo-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Duolingo   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning Japanese for over two years at this point. For my new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution in 2019, I wanted to learn a new language, and I&amp;rsquo;ve stuck with that since. It&amp;rsquo;s probably the only time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever kept one. Duolingo is an excellent resource for learning languages. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily think it&amp;rsquo;s ideal for a language like Japanese, I still use it as it is convenient and simple. Although the ads are quite annoying, I think it is nice overall. I picked up French a couple months ago and I&amp;rsquo;m also trying to learn it at the same time. I think you should diversify your sources to maximize your learning capabilities, as Duolingo isn&amp;rsquo;t good for all aspects of learning a language.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="aftership-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Aftership   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A really good app for tracking packages. If you can sync with your Amazon or eBay account. The package updates aren&amp;rsquo;t always in time for some reason (maybe delayed an hour), but it&amp;rsquo;s good enough, and it&amp;rsquo;s free.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="customization">Customization&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="nova-launcher-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">Nova Launcher   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Best launcher I&amp;rsquo;ve tried. I do not like Samsung&amp;rsquo;s One UI launcher as it is not customizable at all. With Nova Launcher, you can rearrange the app grid, remove app labels, use custom icon packs, hide apps, customize gestures, change animations, change themes, customize app drawers, and more. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a couple of other launchers, but this one has the most features and is compatible with almost every Android feature. It&amp;rsquo;s $4.99 for Nova Prime (more features), and it&amp;rsquo;s worth every penny.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://i.redd.it/vx4gyfv4zy951.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of reddit.com"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
width="400"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of reddit.com&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="kwgt-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">Kwgt   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The all-in-one widget makers. You can literally make any widget provided you have a lot of time to spend. A better idea is to buy widget packs. Some good ones are Shadow and Fusion. Using Kwgt will require you to purchase a key, and icon packs will probably cost money as well. But it&amp;rsquo;s your only option for customizable widgets not provided by your apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EsFAb9NXYAAqAhp.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="One4KWGT Pro"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>One4KWGT Pro&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="flight-icon-packhttpsplaygooglecomstoreappsdetailsidcomnatewrenflighthlen_usglus-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">&lt;a class="link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.natewren.flight&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Flight Icon Pack&lt;/a>   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The icons you see below are from this icon pack. It has thousands of icons, and I really like the clean aesthetic. There are a bunch of default icons you can assign to apps that don&amp;rsquo;t have an icon yet. This is obviously a very personal choice for your home screen, so get the icons you like. The pro version has more icons and costs $1.99.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EBopOx7U0AAOssN.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of Dave2D"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of Dave2D&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="agendahttpsplaygooglecomstoreappsdetailsidcomfrancoagendahlen_usglus-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">&lt;a class="link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.franco.agenda&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Agenda&lt;/a>   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is the best calendar widget I&amp;rsquo;ve used. It allows syncing with any calendar app and categorizes them. The widget is very customizable and lists all your events chronologically. It&amp;rsquo;s 99 cents on the Google Play store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://blog.echen.io/media/images/Screenshot_20210206-234933_Nova7.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Agenda Widget"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Agenda Widget&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="backdrops-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Backdrops   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a wallpaper collection app. Wallpapers are added every few days or so, and you can set them through the app. I learned about this app from MKBHD; he gets some of his wallpapers from it. You have to have particular tastes to enjoy these wallpapers, so they may not suit your needs. I like most of the wallpapers, but I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use them on my phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://www.ytechb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Best-Wallpapers-app-for-Android-Backdrops.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of ytechb.com"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
width="400"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of ytechb.com&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="social-media-alternatives">Social Media Alternatives&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Honestly, I need to get off social media. It is an incredible waste of time most days, and I find myself mindlessly scrolling through reposted and uninteresting content. I agree with Eli in the sense that I should remove these distractions from my homepage and focus on things that matter more. As much as I hate Reddit, it is good for some things, like finding good wallpapers, learning about app updates, and finding excellent photography.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sync-for-reddit-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">Sync for Reddit   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is probably the best Android Reddit app. It has unbelievable customization, and the developer is extremely active and pushes out updates all the time. There are so many features that I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly list them all, but I&amp;rsquo;ll name a few: theme customization (literally every element), dark mode, animations, caching, word filters, and more. I mainly like it because of its clean design and layout flexibility, but there&amp;rsquo;s just something pleasing about being able to customize everything. That&amp;rsquo;s the basis of Android, no? I&amp;rsquo;ve used Apollo for iOS, which is also very good, but I definitely like Sync better. It offers more customizability and theming options, but this is just a personal preference. The ad-free version is $4.99, and it&amp;rsquo;s honestly a steal. You probably won&amp;rsquo;t find anything better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://blog.echen.io/media/uploads/sync.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Sync for Reddit"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Sync for Reddit&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="relay-for-reddit-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Relay for Reddit   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I used this app until I found Sync. It is also very good. It is based on fluid animations and a clean, simple design. Sync is definitely more customizable, but you might be overwhelmed by the tsunami of options. Sometimes, falling back on a simple and clean app is better, and you&amp;rsquo;ll definitely find that with Relay. It has multiple card layouts and preset themes. You can go minimalistic or feature-rich. It&amp;rsquo;s overall a very nice app, but I do like Sync a lot more. The ad-free version is $4.99.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Y4DO74M.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="Relay"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Relay&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="flamingo-for-twitter-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei">Flamingo for Twitter   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This app is also discontinued, and you can&amp;rsquo;t really get it anymore. So why am I mentioning it? First, it still has an incredibly nice design, and it is a very customizable Twitter app. However, I do not recommend it. Twitter&amp;rsquo;s API for developers is some hot garbage. It restricts access to features like favorite notifications, retweet count, and token limits. I doubt this will be changed any time soon, which means all independent Twitter apps are missing out on features only the actual app will have. I do not recommend Twitter apps unless you really like the design, so it&amp;rsquo;s up to you. Having worked with the API, I know the pain of working with free-tier limits.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="games">Games&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>The games I play are not the time-consuming type. They are usually pretty collector-based, so don&amp;rsquo;t expect any triple-A shooter games here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tsuki-adventure-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Tsuki Adventure   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A simple RPG-like app where you collect carrots and roam different areas. You are a small bunny who aims to build relationships and memories with your friends. This game is honestly really cute. There are tons of things to unpack as you go along, and the developers have hidden many secrets. I&amp;rsquo;ve played this game for nearly two years, and I am nowhere near finished. There are some adult jokes too, which is strange considering its innocent artwork and designs. The storyline has some pretty dark points. The Yakuza boss owns the bar in the Mushroom Village? The police chief&amp;rsquo;s daughter died falling through the thinning ice? You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised. It also has events that correlate with real life, like Chinese New Year, Halloween, and Christmas. You have to download it to really understand how this game works because it&amp;rsquo;s probably not what you would expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://i.redd.it/jghb7fcyj7w21.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of reddit.com"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
width="400"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of reddit.com&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="neko-atsume-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Neko Atsume   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A cat collecting game. Your goal is to befriend cats by buying food and decorating your house with cat furniture. There are common and rare cats to collect and house remodeling upgrades. It&amp;rsquo;s simple yet addicting. It takes a while to complete, so you better have some patience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/61JufknUUFL.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of amazon.com"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of amazon.com&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="altos-adventurealtos-odyssey-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Alto&amp;rsquo;s Adventure/Alto&amp;rsquo;s Odyssey   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a clean and elegant endless snowboarding game. Travel different landscapes and scenery while unlocking new boards, abilities, and characters. It&amp;rsquo;s relaxing, and the music is nice. Literally any screenshot you take is wallpaper-worthy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://is5-ssl.mzstatic.com/image/thumb/Purple62/v4/54/cb/4a/54cb4a9c-caad-ed55-ba44-7d2ca85ed3ca/pr_source.png/643x0w.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Frame from Alto&amp;rsquo;s Odyssey"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Frame from Alto&amp;rsquo;s Odyssey&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="monument-valley-2-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-android-stylecolor-3ddc84-aria-hiddentruei-nbsp-i-classfab-fa-apple-aria-hiddentruei">Monument Valley 2   &lt;i class="fab fa-android" style="color: #3DDC84;" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>   &lt;i class="fab fa-apple" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A really cool game with some fascinating designs. It&amp;rsquo;s a puzzle game that revolves around impossible shapes and optical illusions. You operate a princess, modifying landscapes to help her reach the next levels and reconnect with her mother. There is no dialogue, yet it tells a pretty charming story. Some puzzles are genuinely challenging, and the landscapes are seriously beautiful. I only wish this game was longer, but otherwise, I have no complaints. This game has a predecessor, Monument Valley 1. The game costs $4.99, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="image-url">
&lt;img src="https://cdn.cloudflare.steamstatic.com/steam/apps/1927740/ss_dcc6681a9f59237ab1c4b381b0f2aceba0079f78.1920x1080.jpg?t=1657630530"
loading="lazy"
alt="Courtesy of steam.com"
style="display: block;
margin-left: auto;
margin-right: auto;
border-radius: 5px;"
>
&lt;figcaption>Courtesy of steam.com&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="some-others-worth-considering">Some others worth considering:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Games like Genshin Impact and Sky: Children of the Light are open-world RPG-like games. They are processor intensive but with very nice graphics. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be into those types of games, but they don&amp;rsquo;t suit me. I can imagine a lot of people liking them, however.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="concluding-thoughts">Concluding Thoughts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you can probably tell, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty invested in customizing my phone. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty time-consuming, but I like the freedom to customize to my heart&amp;rsquo;s desire. One thing I can say for certain is that I currently spend way too much time on my phone, primarily watching YouTube videos. I think this line from Eli&amp;rsquo;s post about how a phone should function in our lives is pretty good.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Instead of a technology that sucks up time and controls my attention, I want my phone to be the opposite - something that saves me time and frees up attention for important tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We have an unlimited arsenal of tools at our fingertips, and putting it to good use should be its purpose. Starting from now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to build more positive habits and try new things instead of lazily swiping my finger over nonsensical posts on Reddit. My goal is to read &lt;em>Frankenstein&lt;/em> by Mary Shelley within the next few weeks. Expect a blog post with my thoughts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advice to those Applying to University</title><link>https://dev.echen.io/p/advice-to-those-applying-to-university/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dev.echen.io/p/advice-to-those-applying-to-university/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/advice-to-those-applying-to-university/college.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Advice to those Applying to University" />&lt;p>It looks like you&amp;rsquo;re going to start to apply to college soon. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a rough ride, but there are a couple of tips I&amp;rsquo;d like to give you just so you can feel more confident about it. Some of this advice will primarily apply to students at Montgomery Blair, but feel free to look for the parts that apply to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, a little bit of background. I applied to 13 colleges in total: 2 early decisions and 11 regular decisions. They were as follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="early-action">Early Action:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>University of Maryland&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stanford&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="regular-decision">Regular Decision:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Carnegie Mellon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Johns Hopkins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Harvard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Princeton&lt;/li>
&lt;li>University of Pennsylvania&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Massachusetts Institute of Technology&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Northwestern&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Duke&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Columbia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cornell&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>There are quite a few reasons my list consists of these particular colleges. I will explain why, but don&amp;rsquo;t feel pressured to model yours off of it (you don&amp;rsquo;t know how qualified I am yet as most decisions are not out). Generally, most people would want a combination of safety schools, target schools, and reach schools (names are self-explanatory). Generally, if you have a safe school you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable going to, I advise that you only apply to one as it will not be worth the effort to apply to others. For most people in MoCo, UMD would be your pick for this one. It is one of the top-ranked public universities in the nation, nearby, and easy to get into (provided you are a semi-decent student). If you are in Blair, do not be worried, you&amp;rsquo;ll almost definitely get in if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Target schools are those that you feel capable of getting into but are not guaranteed. Students with good GPAs and extracurriculars would probably aim towards mid to top-tier colleges, including schools like Georgia Tech and Northeastern. I did not apply to any target schools, so take my advice with a grain of salt. For most, I would advise applying to only a few target schools, enough so that you feel comfortable getting into one, but don&amp;rsquo;t dwell too much on it. UMD is already an excellent college, and honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s better than most mid-tier schools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find that most people spend their time on prestigious universities, but then again, my friend circle is brimming with hyper-accomplished students. Most people apply to quite a few. These universities are almost always reach schools, which probably means your acceptance is down to luck (for most students, that is). Schools include all your Ivies, MIT, Stanford, etc. There is quite a lot to choose from and a lot of research for you to do to see which ones you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="getting-started">Getting Started&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="so-which-schools-should-i-apply-to">So which schools should I apply to?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well, it depends on who you are. I&amp;rsquo;ll lay out a few strategies and you can either take your pick or devise your own. If you are perfectly comfortable going to UMD and have a few reach schools that you&amp;rsquo;d consider, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to apply to that many. I know of some who just applied to ~5 colleges for that exact reason. If you&amp;rsquo;re set on making a top-tier college, I recommend UMD and a handful of top-tier colleges, and maybe a couple of targets if you don&amp;rsquo;t to go to UMD. I applied to 1 safety school and 12 reach schools because I am perfectly happy with going to UMD, and anything else is just extra. That&amp;rsquo;s why you don&amp;rsquo;t see any mid-tier or mid-to-top tier schools on my list. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard, most people in MoCo apply to 7-15 schools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schools specialize in different majors. If you are a stellar musician, you would probably not apply to the same schools as a prospective engineer. The schools you choose to apply to are based on what you would like to do. If you&amp;rsquo;re a diehard artist, then something like CalTech is not for you. You&amp;rsquo;re going to need to do a lot of research. I recommend accessing the university&amp;rsquo;s homepage, blogs of alumni, &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ApplyingToCollege/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>college subreddits&lt;/a>, or online guides/lists (like USNews). If you have friends or family who went to or currently attends university, they can be an invaluable asset to your application process. Try to reach out as much as possible; it can&amp;rsquo;t hurt you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fiske-Guide-Colleges-2021-Edward/dp/1492664960" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Fiske&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Colleges&lt;/a> for some basic research. It&amp;rsquo;s a comprehensive guide of all the universities in the United States. It will tell you about price ranges, general academic markers, and the specialties of each school. You can purchase it with the link or pirate it with Libgen. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t tell you about the latter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, don&amp;rsquo;t just go off of what I have said. Ask other seniors or recent graduates as well. Talk to your parents and friends to get their perspective. After all, that&amp;rsquo;s where most of my information came from. Don&amp;rsquo;t stress too much about it; you&amp;rsquo;ll get the gist eventually.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-mindset">The Mindset&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I genuinely believe that having the mindset that you must go to a top-tier college is harmful. Most people don&amp;rsquo;t end up at the best schools and that&amp;rsquo;s okay. Being a hard worker at a lower-tier college can net you many benefits and may even be better suited towards you. However, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard not to have this mindset in Montgomery County due to the vast amount of accomplished individuals, and I am honestly part of the problem. I think the best thing to remember is that you will be okay. When you look back at yourself in 50 years, which college you went to won&amp;rsquo;t be in the top 10 most important events in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try for the top-tier colleges. If you&amp;rsquo;re capable, why not? Just note that it likely isn&amp;rsquo;t as important as others make it out to be. I rode the hype train and honestly, the only reason I want to make it into a top-tier college is just for my ego. I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily think it will get me a better education overall. If even I think I will be fine, you should have confidence in yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="early-and-regular-decisions-whats-the-difference">Early and Regular Decisions. What&amp;rsquo;s the difference?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So there are a couple of differences and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain it as best as I can, as there is often some confusion surrounding this topic. Early applications have an earlier deadline (around November 1st) and are split into two categories: &lt;strong>Early Decision (ED) and Early Action (EA).&lt;/strong> ED schools are binding schools. If you apply and get in with the early decision, you are legally bound to that school and cannot go to another. They are usually your top pick, as you will not have the flexibility to choose another university if you get in. If you don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip;then you will have that flexibility. Early Action schools are also submitted early but are not binding. It&amp;rsquo;s just getting your decision earlier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what&amp;rsquo;s the benefit? Generally, ED and EA appear to give you a higher chance of admission, as you are showing high interest in the school. But don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled; the acceptance rate probably won&amp;rsquo;t be the deciding factor. Furthermore, you just get your decision way earlier, so you can determine how to proceed with the application process depending on whether you get in or not. You can only apply to one ED school, so be sure it&amp;rsquo;s your top choice. Most EA schools are restrictive, meaning you can also only apply to one, but private schools like MIT and Caltech and most public schools allow you to apply to more than one (just make sure the others are not restrictive). Note the difference between public and private universities. Restrictive EA for private universities means you can still EA to public universities. They are independent of one another. Most people will either pick EA or ED, but the possibility of applying to both may suit your needs. Many of my friends applied to 4+ schools early.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regular Decisions have a later application deadline, usually due around January 1st. But check the school you are applying to, as some may have a deadline earlier or even much later. You can apply to everything else you didn&amp;rsquo;t apply to in ED/EA, with almost no restrictions. Since most ED/EA decisions are released before January 1st, make sure you modify your strategy accordingly. Say you got accepted into your ED school. There is no further need for you to apply to any other schools, as you cannot attend them anyway. Just be happy that you are done. If you get in EA, you can still apply to more schools, as it will give you more options later down the line if you do get into any of your RD schools. It is completely up to you whether you want to do that or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of my friends applied for EA as it gives you more flexibility. But if you &lt;em>really&lt;/em> have that dream school and it is ED, go right on ahead. I believe in you. However, if you have the choice of EA or ED for the same school, EA is probably the way to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-application-process-what-is-my-timeline">The Application Process: What is my timeline?&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>There are five key aspects of the application process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Filling out Common App/other portals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Essays and supplementals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Teacher Recommendations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transcripts and Test Scores&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Although the college process is quite simple, it can easily overwhelm you. Since essays will be the most difficult and time-consuming portion of your app, start with the others first. I recommend asking your teachers for recommendations as early as you can. If you can get it done before your junior year ends, that would be ideal. I requested my recommendations in August, which is still fine, but the earlier the better. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to fill them out until the deadline for your colleges, but make sure they know they are writing you one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next step is the planning process. You need to decide which colleges you want to apply to. I stress that you need to make sure you are willing to go to the schools you apply to. There is no reason for filler schools; it will only waste your time and money. After you decide on a rough list, highlight the ones you are definitely applying to and the schools you will apply to early. If you are unsure whether you will apply to a college, it&amp;rsquo;s fine. You will have time to decide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get started on your common app. Most schools will use the common app. You will need to fill in a lot of personal information, including your grades, academics, and honors. This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take very long. You can update your achievements as you go, but fill out the trivial stuff as soon as you can. At this point, you should request transcripts for the schools you are set on. You can do it as you go, but make sure to submit the request on Naviance (for MoCo students) at least 20 days in advance. Make sure you know which schools require direct test scores for APs, SATs, ACTs, or whatnot because you will need to request scores from College Board (etc.) and have your scores sent to your schools. This will cost a bit of cash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The steps above are quite easy but annoying. Just get them done early so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to panic about it as I did. Making a spreadsheet detailing your actions will help you greatly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="essays-of-death">Essays of Death&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The next step is your essays. The common app essay is the default BIG essay where you pour your heart into something especially important about yourself. It&amp;rsquo;s 650 words and will take a long time. You must make sure you have a unique and interesting idea. The prompts are &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.commonapp.org/apply/essay-prompts" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>here&lt;/a> (for 2021-2022). The prompts are vague enough that you can literally talk about anything, so make sure it stands out. You can probably find better advice for how to write essays from other people, so I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the details here. Know that there will be a lot of editing and rewriting. Put yourself on a piece of paper and make it riveting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each school will have supplemental essays, which can range from just one to eight (thanks, Stanford) or more essays. Some will be short (50ish words) and some will be long (400-600 words). Common prompts include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Why our school?&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Name a contribution to your community&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>How will you integrate into our school&amp;rsquo;s community?&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Describe your background.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Each essay will require a lot of brainstorming and a lot of writing, so be prepared for the long haul. Generally, you will want to work on one school at a time. You will be able to reuse essays and snippets across multiple schools, so plan out the most efficient path for you to conquer them all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bulk of your time will be editing your work. Use good rhetoric and use words that bring out your writing style. You will need to research colleges and learn a lot about them to write about them. For the &amp;ldquo;Why us&amp;rdquo; questions, read about clubs, the community, classes, and programs. Make a list of the things you liked and connect these ideas to who you are today and who you want to be. Again, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to include too many writing tips here, as there are plenty of resources at your fingertips. Good online resources include the &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.collegeessayguy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>CollegeEssayGuy&lt;/a> and &lt;a class="link" href="https://blog.collegevine.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>CollegeVine&lt;/a>, but the best resources will likely be your friends, mentors, and family. Ask for help&amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;ll indubitably save your ass some trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would like to reiterate that the essays are time-consuming. Try to start at least a month before your deadline. You will spend weeks polishing, writing, and refining. Doing things earlier will take the stress off your shoulders and help you stay calm as the deadlines approach. You want to feel like you have an uncessary amount of time to write and edit. If you have trouble getting started, ask a friend to help you brainstorm. Once you&amp;rsquo;re done with a school&amp;rsquo;s requirements, you will be able to submit. Save some time to look over your common app and fix the silly mistakes. Nervously chide yourself that you did everything correctly as you enter in your credit card information and click the submit button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember, this guide is just a broad outline of things you will need to do. The content is only surface-level insight because most of your experience will be gained throughout the gruelling process itself. I will be here if you want to reach out, and I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to talk to you or even look at your essays. But I hope I can instill some confidence into you as these difficult months approach. Having an outline of what needs to be done can be greatly beneficial, and it&amp;rsquo;s something I wish I had. Planning will be your best friend. Putting the minute details on paper will greatly reduce the fog around you. &lt;strong>You got this.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not do a great job during the college application process. I did not even begin writing my common app until three weeks before my first deadline, and I did not settle on a final idea until two before. I was extremely anxious and incredibly exhausted every day. For the first school I applied to, I was still writing on the last hour of the last day, watching the clock nervously as the seconds ticked by. After I finished my Early Action schools, I took too long of a break as I was tired beyond belief; a big blunder. For my Regular Decision applications, I turned everything in on the day it was due, less than an hour before the deadline. I had seldom time to polish my essays and relied on massive aid from my sister and her friend. Despite this, I believe I was able to crank out some solid essays, but they definitely could have been better if I allotted my time wisely. I believe you can learn from my mistakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you finish applications, the bulk of the work is done. However, it&amp;rsquo;s not time to celebrate quite yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interviews">Interviews&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The last step is the interviews. Shortly after you apply to colleges, alumni of the schools you applied to will email you for an interview. This can take weeks, so be patient. Many schools will offer you the choice to opt out, but I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend it. Interviews are an opportunity for you to show the schools what you are like in real life, so you should use it to your advantage. The charming words on paper won&amp;rsquo;t masquerade you in front of another person, so be prepared. The interviewer will ask you questions and report back to the school with an essay about your conversation. Although it was over Zoom for my year, it will likely return to in-person meetings at a coffee shop or a restaurant next year. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard, most alumni do not know the scope the interview has on your decision. The general consensus among students is that a bad interview can screw you over and a good one will only confirm what the admission officer already knows. This is pure speculation, so take it with a colossal grain of salt. Nevertheless, you want to shine like a star. Brush up on the school&amp;rsquo;s interview policies because some schools don&amp;rsquo;t offer them or might not have space left to offer you one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I highly recommend studying up on the school before your interview. Know how to answer the commonly asked questions, like &amp;ldquo;describe yourself&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;why did you apply to [this school]&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;what is your biggest weakness.&amp;rdquo; The conversation is usually more relaxed than you expect, so there&amp;rsquo;s no need to tense up. Try to act human; you don&amp;rsquo;t want the interviewer to see you as only stats on a piece of paper. Talk to them like you&amp;rsquo;re trying to impress your parents&amp;rsquo; friends. The interviewer isn&amp;rsquo;t going to intentionally trip you up; he or she&amp;rsquo;s just trying to see if you&amp;rsquo;re a good fit for the school and whether they like you, so don&amp;rsquo;t spend the entire hour boasting about your achievements. I recommend memorizing a few memorable experiences or activities that show growth or something important about you. By doing this, you can direct any interview question towards one of these topics and engage the interviewer with meaningful and interesting stories. Look online and learn how to build rapport and be confident. One great YouTube channel for this is &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/charismaoncommand" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Charisma on Command&lt;/a>, from whom I learned many tricks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Try to stand out. Instead of saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m doing well,&amp;rdquo; say &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m doing fantastic&amp;rdquo; or something descriptive that most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say. You want to leave a good impression and have a nice conversation. Put yourself in a good mood before meeting your interviewers&amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;ll go a long way, making you more confident and upbeat. Once you have finished, you&amp;rsquo;re essentially done. You can still submit an update to some schools about new achievements, but now it&amp;rsquo;s time to wait. I&amp;rsquo;m in that process now. You should find meaningful and interesting activities in the meantime, as it will be your last semester in high school. Your life is about your activities and relationships. Have some fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Remember: the college application process isn&amp;rsquo;t complicated, it&amp;rsquo;s tedious. Doing things up front will reduce the stress for your future self. Being organized will make you confident that you are doing things correctly and efficiently. Feel free to email me at &lt;strong>eric chen 314 at gmail dot com&lt;/strong> if you have any questions or would like some advice. I want to help you to do better than I did. If you want, I am willing to send you some essays I wrote for my schools. All you have to do is ask.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Best of luck!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Be okay with not knowing for sure what might come next but know that whatever it is&amp;hellip; you will be okay.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>My Favorite YouTube Channels</title><link>https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:20:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/youtube_logo_dark.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My Favorite YouTube Channels" />&lt;p>I have been watching a lot of YouTube recently, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my favorites by category. I hope you can find one you like out of the bunch. Note: many people fall into multiple categories, but I tried my best to separate them. A list of all the channels I mention will be at the bottom. Alert: this will be a very long post.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="commentary-channels">Commentary Channels&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/75y73mf3tkc41.png"
width="803"
height="705"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/75y73mf3tkc41_hu5110ac33e7b3ad230d3cc32f4d3021cc_374638_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/75y73mf3tkc41_hu5110ac33e7b3ad230d3cc32f4d3021cc_374638_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Big stinker Drew Gooden"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="113"
data-flex-basis="273px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like commentary channels a lot, and I have watched quite a handful of them. I recently found a guy named Drew Gooden, and he&amp;rsquo;s very entertaining. He is very sarcastic yet mellow, even when he&amp;rsquo;s mad. His commentary is funny and relatable, and I like the consistency throughout his videos. He discusses all sorts of topics, including the infamous Paul Brothers, dumb arts and crafts channels, and movies. I think he is underrated, and you should check him out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some other notable commentary channels are PewDiePie and H3H3. PewDiePie&amp;rsquo;s content often involves discussing Youtube controversy, going through his subreddit, or playing video games. It does get a little bit repetitive, but he is very likable, and he generates well-edited videos. It gives me a sense of being part of a community. I wish he would vary his content a bit more in the future. H3H3 is a pretty controversial channel, and I have found myself watching him less, but he is funny nonetheless. He&amp;rsquo;s not afraid to say what he thinks, and he makes fun of people as well as himself. Hila, his wife, is pretty much the opposite of him, but they have a great dynamic. I don&amp;rsquo;t like H3H3 on Twitter as much, but a lot of his content is golden, but I can see why people think he&amp;rsquo;s disturbing because he is a bit crazy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last one is Mother&amp;rsquo;s Basement. He does commentary on anime. He does a lot of research and puts a lot of time into his videos, and it really shows. He discusses what makes great films great, and what makes horrible films horrible. He is able to take a lot of meaning out of scenes and has shown me a lot about what an anime&amp;rsquo;s central theme was. He is funny and likable, and his videos are very well crafted and organized.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comedy-channels">Comedy Channels&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I have a few favorites in mind: NigaHiga, Casually Explained, and You Suck at Cooking (YSAC). NigaHiga has been around forever, and I grew up with his videos. He has created amazing skits, ranted about topics like racism and swearing, and has produced some amazing and unique series (Skitzo, ParkCourse, DearRyan). He is extremely likable and funny, and his ideas are as original as they get. He is good at acting as multiple characters, and I like every single person in his studio (RIP Sean). His videos are seriously top-notch, and you can tell that he spends a lot of time on them, all for his audience. He has gradually lost viewers, but I seriously believe he is one of the most underrated channels of modern YouTube.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/Casually-Explained-Interview-header-Image-htxt.africa.png"
width="800"
height="450"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/Casually-Explained-Interview-header-Image-htxt.africa_hua7c6a24a2a13b1f0d37efdf69e64c474_157681_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/Casually-Explained-Interview-header-Image-htxt.africa_hua7c6a24a2a13b1f0d37efdf69e64c474_157681_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Casually Explained&amp;rsquo;s first encounter with a woman"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Casually Explained (CE) and YSAC are similar channels. Both are very sarcastic and entertaining. CE uses simplistic yet iconic drawings and talks about a lot of common issues (relationships, diets, banking) with a monotone voice. He is extremely sarcastic and every single joke lands really hard and is very thought out. He relies on the misery of his primarily male audience and has a depressing tone in every video, but it is seriously golden. His silly drawings really bring out the comedic effect of his videos, and he actually teaches you stuff at the same time, even though most of it is a joke. YSAC is a cooking channel, where he does comedy through cooking. His videos are all original with the same tinge of sarcasm and slapstick humor as CE. His repetition of inside jokes throughout his videos always make me chuckle. You have to watch him to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. He can sing (not in the way you might think), play instruments, cook, make jokes, and put cute animals all into one video without making it weird. Absolutely incredible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tech-channels">Tech Channels&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I really like technology, almost to a fault. I want stuff that I will never be able to get, but I watch these videos anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My favorites channels are MKBHD, Dave2D, and LinusTechTips. MKBHD is one of the most popular tech channels on YouTube. He buys a LOT of expensive stuff and puts it into good use. His videos are very stylish and punchy, and all the shots he uses are amazing. He is very extreme with tech, and you like tech because he likes tech. He talks about smartphones, TVs, electric cars, and more. His editing is spot on and the way he talks about technology is very easy to consume. The variety he brings out makes every video seem fresh and new, and he has seriously conquered the YT algorithm. He uses nearly NO clickbait at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dave2D does YouTube on the side. His videos are extremely clean and his film work is simple yet refined. He has a soothing voice and he is very efficient. He gets videos done in like half the time of other channels but covers the same amount of content. Recently, he&amp;rsquo;s been discussing more of what a new product means to the market, and you can really learn new things. He prefers a certain aesthetic to all his products, and I share that aesthetic. His videos are efficient and have good style, and he is very thorough and covers topics as a consumer rather than a &amp;ldquo;guy who has everything.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/maxresdefault.jpg"
width="1280"
height="720"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/maxresdefault_hu5067c088682eaa063248d5939acc5428_83516_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/maxresdefault_hu5067c088682eaa063248d5939acc5428_83516_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Linus Tech Tips"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linus Tech Tips (LTT) is probably the most educational of the bunch. You can seriously learn something about technology/computer science in nearly all his videos. He cares a lot about things like gaming monitors and peripherals, and he knows a lot of his audience is too. He is very opinionated and controversial, and you&amp;rsquo;ll either love the way he creates videos or you&amp;rsquo;ll hate them. Linus is a very hard worker and covers every base in the tech world. His team is very likable and they do a lot of interesting things with tech, and his reviews are extremely thorough.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="skit-channels">Skit Channels&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Skits are really fun because they&amp;rsquo;re short and easy to watch. I know that SNL and CollegeHumor are pretty popular, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really watch those. My favorite skit channels are Studio C (cast moved to JK! Studios), CalebCity, and ProZD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Studio C is a family-friendly skit channel that plays on BYU-TV, but everything they do is on YouTube. The original cast (who I like the most) has now moved to JK! Studios to pursue something new. But all the old videos on Studio C are golden. The cast is extremely talented, funny, and diverse. Everyone has their own kinks and unique traits, and I honestly love all of them. Their skits are amazingly original, and they always pick the best people to play the part. They can do accents, sing and dance, and dress up in hilarious costumes. Sometimes they publish skits where people break character, and honestly, that makes it even better. I recommend watching the older stuff from Studio C, and I think you&amp;rsquo;ll really enjoy it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/f9a2849e2e864f47670447765c13a0af.jpg"
width="1280"
height="720"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/f9a2849e2e864f47670447765c13a0af_hud98dbc27094ad540b7b99c8182bcc713_44149_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/f9a2849e2e864f47670447765c13a0af_hud98dbc27094ad540b7b99c8182bcc713_44149_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="CalebCity&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;If life glitched like video games&amp;rdquo;"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CalebCity is a skit channel ran by Caleb, a former Viner-turned-YouTuber. He usually plays all the characters in his skits, hence, Caleb &amp;ldquo;City&amp;rdquo;. He sticks to very relatable topics, and his skits are also very funny and original. They are short, but they always get the theme across. You know there will always be a plot twist, where his skits devolve into punching, screaming, or feet falling off. It&amp;rsquo;s honestly hilarious, and his crude-yet-refined editing and sound effects make it that much better. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the same studio-level production tools, and his creative ways of implementing the same effect are outright amazing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ProZD is a chubby Asian guy who makes a lot of really short skits (he is a voice actor). Like CalebCity, he plays all the characters and films himself. He has a different sort of style, and he is also very creative. He sticks to topics like card games, anime, and relatable topics, and his tone and slapstick humor makes even his 10 second videos great to watch. Honorable Mention: NigaHiga also makes a lot of great skits, but I already mentioned him earlier. They have great production quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gaming">Gaming&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>First off, I am not a gamer. I do not have the peripherals to play even basic titles, and I would also probably get addicted. Most of my gaming consists of playing Wii, Nintendo Switch, and GameCube. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge Nintendo sucker; I love the Mario series, and one of my favorite games ever is &amp;ldquo;Super Mario Galaxy 2&amp;rdquo;. The music is great, the gameplay is fantastic, and I would really like to be able to buy a console so I can play more when I have the money. I like Tetris a lot. I know it seems super lame, but I recommend you try it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have only ever watched a few channels in my life, but I enjoy them nonetheless. They are TheRunawayGuys (I&amp;rsquo;ll be specific) and JosephSaelee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/trg.jpg"
width="1280"
height="720"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/trg_hu240b259b147e9fed4c1487d68255983e_126383_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/trg_hu240b259b147e9fed4c1487d68255983e_126383_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Drawing of TheRunAwayGuys (left to right: Tim, Jon, Chugga)"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Runawayguys (TRG) consists of ChuggaaConroy (Emile), ProtonJon (Jon), and NintendoCapriSun (Tim). They have also collaborated with MasaeAnela (Masae) and JoshJepson (Josh). I literally love all of them. They play multiplayer games such as Brawl, Super Mario, Kirby, and a lot of Nintendo games (kind of my jam). They have very good chemistry. Chugga is silly and crazy, but he is also really good at the games. I would say Jon is probably the best player of the bunch, and also the most intellectual and sane. Chugga and Jon are the &amp;ldquo;hate each other&amp;rdquo; best friends, and they always mess with each other and get mad at each other, usually stemming from Chugga pissing off Jon and Jon trying to kill him (in the game). Tim is usually quiet but he says a bunch of super weird but funny stuff and he is honestly super chill and somehow essential to the group. Josh is the crazy one with the crazy high-pitched voice and a lot of energy. He usually plays when there need to be 4 players in a game (e.g. Super Mario Bros), and he makes the LPs more lively. Masae also has a feud with Chugga (they are also shipped a lot), but she is really sweet and is a really nice addition to the sausage fest sometimes. They all share fantastic and exciting moments throughout all of the LPs, and you really get to know them and what they are good at. You feel like they are also your friends, and honestly, I wish I could play with friends more often after watching them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside of TRG, I probably watch Chugga the most, and only the games I&amp;rsquo;ve actually played myself. He does a lot of research before playing the games, and he talks a lot about the creation of the game. He gives you a lot of information about characters&amp;rsquo; design, and flaws in every episode, and you actually learn from him. He is a really cool guy, but he is also kind of insane, but probably in a good way. You&amp;rsquo;ll get what I mean if you watch him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joseph Saelee is not really a gaming channel. He plays Tetris, and he is regarded as the best player alive today. He is 18 (I think), and he is really good. I watch him because he really can play better than any other pro-Tetris player, and he constantly breaks records. He is also charismatic, which adds to the appeal. His content isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly interesting if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to look for, but I find it calming. The matches he has with other people are actually somewhat exciting, and I recommend you check them out on the Official Tetris channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honorable Mentions: Ninja. I watched him because he was good at Fortnite when he was popular (not so much anymore), and it was fun to see him rage and own players. I know a lot of people hate him, but I found him pretty entertaining. I don&amp;rsquo;t watch him anymore, but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s fun watching the best of the best. I&amp;rsquo;m leaving this in the past.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="educational">Educational&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I think it&amp;rsquo;s really valuable to learn something on YouTube. There are millions of resources and you can find almost everything. I like watching the ones that are also entertaining.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are Kurzgesagt and Charisma on Command.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/kgsagt.jpeg"
width="1536"
height="864"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/kgsagt_hu5d725a75a2562e172a0c714a4b2b793e_159845_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/kgsagt_hu5d725a75a2562e172a0c714a4b2b793e_159845_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Kurzgesagt animation frame"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kurzgesagt is a narration-over-animation channel. They dive deep into real topics in science, such as black holes, the immune system, and climate change. They gather information from many professionals and explain it to the audience in a really simple and elegant way. The visuals are eye-candy, and they seriously put a ton of effort into their videos. They discuss really fascinating topics, and it has really exposed me to a bunch of cool science I would have never considered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charisma on Command teaches you how to be more charismatic and sociable. They discuss what to do and what not to do, often distributing the information in a numbered list. They also analyze celebrities and tell you what they do right and what they do wrong (e.g. Jordan Peterson, Donald Trump, and Brie Larson). It has helped me realize what makes my social interactions weak and boring, and I&amp;rsquo;m really trying to get better. They offer really detailed videos, and I think anyone can learn how to become more charismatic. I think this is really important, as I want to become a leader and really be able to engage with other people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honorable Mentions: Crash Course teaches literally every school topic, but it is really specific to you WANTING to learn something. It&amp;rsquo;s more difficult to just pick a video randomly and watch it. They hire professionals in their fields (like Hank and John), and their videos are very thorough and refined. Veritasium also makes good content. It is a guy who travels around to learn more about science, and his videos discuss topics from aerogel to radiation. I&amp;rsquo;m not as familiar with his content, however. The last one is Daily Dose of Internet. He compiles videos of insane things, from amazing scenery to intelligent dogs and feats of extreme athleticism. The videos are short and are a rapid-fire compilation style, and his narration is soothing. They are cool videos and nice to watch when you want to relax. ASAPScience makes animated videos too. They are good for the common person, and the videos are very informational and surprising. Worth a look.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mentioned these channels already, but they can be classified as education. A lot of Linus&amp;rsquo;s (LTT) channels are educational, and they teach you a lot about computers and technology (e.g. displays, networking, CPUs). Casually Explained is also loosely educational but entertaining.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="music">Music&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>People make a lot of music on YouTube. A lot of people are really creative and I like a lot of them. I listen to a lot of music, but there are a few channels where I usually watch more than one video. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t regard musicians like Hillary Hahn or Jascha Heifetz to be YouTubers, so I have chosen not to include them. Also, I guess artists like 20syl or Taylor Swift do not really make &amp;ldquo;entertaining&amp;rdquo; content, so I also will not include artists who just make music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/StudioTwoSet-Violin0821-banner.jpg"
width="2500"
height="1404"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/StudioTwoSet-Violin0821-banner_hu7aef838c4248e3b07272ddb352a772d1_359967_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/StudioTwoSet-Violin0821-banner_hu7aef838c4248e3b07272ddb352a772d1_359967_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="TwoSetViolin: Brett Yang (left), Eddy Chen (right)"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="178"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My favorite is TwoSetViolin. TwoSet consists of two Australian violinists that make comedic videos. They are very quirky and talk about a lot of music-related stuff. A lot of it is roasting fake musicians, cracking lame jokes, and playing charades on the violin. I really connect with them because I, too, play the violin. Their jokes do get a bit repetitive, but they are very charming and their videos are hilarious and fun to watch. They are also good musicians, having gone to music school and playing in professional orchestras. You probably won&amp;rsquo;t watch them for their own playing, but it is worth staying for the comedy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honorable Mentions: Paint. He makes those videos where you sing all the parts yourself. He is very good at it, and also he adds a little bit of acting to all of them. He has a crude sense of humor, but his videos are fantastic nonetheless. He hasn&amp;rsquo;t been active in a while, but the videos are still very fun to watch. I recommend the &amp;ldquo;After Ever After&amp;rdquo; series. The Piano Guys. It is a band with a pianist, cellist, vocalist, and editor/set up guy. They have very creative videos to showcase their music, and they create fabulous remixes of pop and classical music (and movie stuff). They sound amazing, and they go to places all across the world (e.g. the Great Wall) to achieve the intended effect of the piece. Their videos are very entertaining and very nice to look at. Sungha Jung. He plays guitar and remixes a lot of random songs (K-Pop, normal pop, movie music). He&amp;rsquo;s really good at the guitar. His videos aren&amp;rsquo;t the most consumable, but it is worthwhile to appreciate the amazing talent he possesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="miscellaneous">Miscellaneous&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>There are some channels that I watch, but don&amp;rsquo;t fit into a category I watch very often. Here are some of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SuperCarlinBrothers. They create movie/book analysis and theory videos, mainly about Harry Potter, Pixar, and Star Wars. It consists of Jay and Ben, two brothers. Their theories are very well crafted and believable, and they dive amazingly deep into the books and movies to pull the information. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of dedication and hard work, and they are also very exciting and fun. The videos are creative as heck, and the theories are really worth a watch, mostly if you are a Harry Potter, Star Wars, Pixar, or Disney fan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Binging with Babish. He makes cooking videos, and they are much more &amp;ldquo;cooking-like&amp;rdquo; than YSAC. The recipes are very thought out, and he goes above and beyond to showcase them. I like to watch him make food, and not do it it myself. He also cracks jokes sometimes, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s really comedy-centric. He makes recipes based on movie items, such as the &amp;ldquo;Krabby Patty&amp;rdquo; from Spongebob. He appears to be good at cooking, but it is still worth the watch anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vat19. They are literally a commercial online shop, and all of their videos are commercials. But they sell stuff I want, like giant candy, color-changing putty, and wobbly wine glasses. The people in the videos are really funny, and they somehow make a commercial fun to watch. They have common tropes in their videos, and they do a lot of skits to promote their products. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever buy from them, but the channel is still very fun, even if you&amp;rsquo;re a big man like me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Domics. Domics is an animation channel, where he talks about relatable issues, such as relationships, pet peeves, and interesting events in his life (a lot of it is anecdotal). He is really good at animating, and you can see his progress throughout his videos. He is fun and has a unique take on a lot of situations, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to go down a rabbit hole when watching his videos. He is Asian too, and I probably relate to stuff because I am Asian too. He is Filipino, so don&amp;rsquo;t get confused!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/carlsen.jpg"
width="1280"
height="720"
srcset="https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/carlsen_hue647ea642fd8b89be7631a1d748447e7_169325_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://dev.echen.io/p/my-favorite-youtube-channels/carlsen_hue647ea642fd8b89be7631a1d748447e7_169325_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Magnus Carlsen Chess24 Banter Blitz"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, man. Chess has become a real time-consuming pastime for me. If you are getting started, you must watch Magnus Carlsen&amp;rsquo;s Banter Blitz series. He provides insight into his genius, monotone jokes, and unbelievable gameplay. It&amp;rsquo;s not obvious why he makes particular chess moves, but it can still be a valuable learning experience. He&amp;rsquo;s just interesting, which makes it that much fun. He has recently gotten WAY better at explaining his moves. It&amp;rsquo;s a privilege for modern chess players. If you would like to take things more slowly, I highly recommend Agadmator&amp;rsquo;s Chess Channel. He explains things very simply and elegantly, and he is almost unintentionally funny, saying ridiculous things with no emotion. It is great for anyone who wants to analyze chess games by the top Grandmasters. Though I have not really watched GMHikaru, Anish Giri, or other GM Youtube channels, I know a lot of them are very popular and probably very good. I&amp;rsquo;ll link some of them below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>End note: I&amp;rsquo;m subscribed to a ton of channels. I love YouTube, and the people who make the content I watch work very hard. I have probably missed some, but this list should be close enough. I can update it over time if I remember or find new channels. If you made it this far, let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a prize!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;All the world&amp;rsquo;s a stage, the men and women are merely players&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; &lt;cite>Shakespeare&lt;/cite>
&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="commentary">Commentary&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCTSRIY3GLFYIpkR2QwyeklA" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Drew Gooden&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/PewDiePie" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>PewDiePie&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/h3h3Productions" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>H3H3 Productions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBs2Y3i14e1NWQxOGliatmg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Mother&amp;rsquo;s Basement&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="comedy">Comedy&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/nigahiga" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>nigahiga&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCr3cBLTYmIK9kY0F_OdFWFQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Casually Explained&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCekQr9znsk2vWxBo3YiLq2w" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>You Suck at Cooking&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="technology">Technology&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/marquesbrownlee" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MKBHD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCVYamHliCI9rw1tHR1xbkfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Dave2D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/LinusTechTips" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Linus Tech Tips&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skits">Skits&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/BYUTelevision" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Studio C&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZDj6Ig-gxkHWzZyQSdGq0Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>JK! Studios&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/GizzlyB3aver" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>CalebCity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ProZD" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>ProZD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="gaming-1">Gaming&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/TheRunawayGuys" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>TheRunawayGuys&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9yubS4W7CdoD5F8RNz4Fuw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Joseph Saelee&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/chuggaaconroy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>ChuggaaConroy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ProtonJonSA" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>ProtonJon&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/MasaeAnela" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>MasaeAnela&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/NintendoCapriSun" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>NintendoCaprisun&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/JoshJepson" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>JoshJepson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/NinjasHyper" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Ninja&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="education">Education&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Kurzgesagt" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Kurzgesagt&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/charismaoncommand" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Charisma on Command&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/crashcourse" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Crash Course&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/1veritasium" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Veritasium&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdC0An4ZPNr_YiFiYoVbwaw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Daily Dose of Internet&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/AsapSCIENCE" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>AsapSCIENCE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="music-1">Music&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/twosetviolin" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>TwoSetViolin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Paint" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Paint&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ThePianoGuys" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>The Piano Guys&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/jwcfree" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Sungha Jung&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="misc">Misc.&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/jwcfree" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>SuperCarlinBrothers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/bgfilms" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Binging with Babish&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/vat19com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Vat19&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/D0MICS" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Domics&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chess
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkTCNuQ2mGfW6-SpHpaze_g" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>chess24&lt;/a> and &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbYSIeioCenYhCBkTeH6F0g/featured" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>chess24.5&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCL5YbN5WLFD8dLIegT5QAbA" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Agadmator&amp;rsquo;s Chess Channel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCweCc7bSMX5J4jEH7HFImng" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>GMHikaru&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9Zs0DGUuenE23tObR50jJQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Anish Giri&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHP9CdeguNUI-_nBv_UXBhw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Daniel Naroditsky&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>